靜 水 城
我們清理完後 這座城市會怎樣?
- 他們會重建它
那些人 他們都會回來嗎?
大多數人 會回來的 真是太瘋狂了
我不覺得美國人喜歡改變
我也不覺得龍捲風在乎美國人喜歡什麼
感謝你選擇聲波
Thank you for making my Sonic your Sonic.
聲波 (Sonic) : 總部位於俄克拉荷馬州的全美自駕連鎖快餐店
我是麥凱拉 今晚需要些什麼?
My name is McKayla. How can I help you tonight?
我要份加芥末和洋蔥的大號奶酪康尼
I need a Footlong Cheese Coney with mustard and onions,
大桶薯條和大杯櫻桃橙汁
large Tots and a large Cherry Limeade.
我們正在向人們
We're on the road showing
展示奧克西林的強去污能力
real people the stain-fighting power of OxiClean.
感謝主 為這和許多其他的祝福
Thank you, Lord, for this and many other blessings.
請繼續守護艾莉
Please keep a watchful eye over Ally.
謹奉基督之名 阿門
In Jesus' name. Amen.
你知道那有多麻煩嗎?
Do you know how annoying that is?
更別說你那麼做可能會傷到自己的眼睛
Not to mention you could blow out your eye that way.
- 你從哪來的?  - 靜水
- Where you from?  - Stillwater.
你最後在哪家鑽井公司工作?
Who's the last drilling company you worked for?
- ITA  - 為什麼不幹了?
- ITA.  - Why'd you quit?
操作員搞壞了鑽機 停工了
Operator dropped the rig. We stacked.
六個月前 我被解雇了
I got laid off six months ago.
你現在在做什麼?
What are you doing now?
從事建築工作
I work construction.
但自從鑽井平台停機以來 就沒什麼事
But it's been slow since the rig's been down.
肖尼龍捲風過後 我一直在做清理工作
I've been doing cleanup after that tornado by Shawnee.
盡我所能
Getting after it.
嗨 莎倫
Hey, Sharon.
讓我看完這一頁
Let me finish this page.
再看一頁
One more page.
感謝您賜予的飲食和所有美好的事物
Thank you for this food and for all that is good in this world.
請繼續守護艾莉森
Keep Allison in your watchful eye.
- 阿門  - 阿門
- Amen.  - Amen.
你找到工作了嗎?
You get hired out yet?
還沒有
Nope.
我今天早上去面試了
Had an interview this morning.
前幾天你媽媽打過電話
Got a call from your mother a few days ago.
她搬到坦帕了
She moved to Tampa.
她要錢還是什麼?
She ask for money or some shit?
不是
No.
她問起你了
She asked about you.
你有空給她打個電話
You should call her sometime.
我這裡的事都夠多了
I got enough I'm dealing with here.
你拿到我的車牌了嗎?
Did you pick up my car registration?
拿到了
Yeah.
我在家裡就拿到了
I got it at home.
我一上午都在等它
Spent all morning waiting for it.
在線辦的
Got it online.
一切都是在線
Everything's online.
如果去現場辦理 根本找不到人
Can't get a real human being if you try.
但他們收了23美元費用
Didn't stop them from charging me $23.
我會付的
I'll pay it.
我不是這個意思
That's not what I meant.
我知道
I know.
門口有個袋子是給你帶去的
There's a bag of things by the front door for you to take.
桌子上還有個裝有照片的信封
And an envelope of photos in on her desk.
那些都很重要
Those are important.
好的 你有兩次中途停留
Okay, you have two stopovers,
第一次在亞特蘭大 第二次在法蘭克福
the first in Atlanta, the second in Frankfurt.
- 在22號登機口  - 謝謝
- You're at gate 22.  - Thank you.
女士們先生們 我們已經開始降落藍色海岸的馬賽普羅旺斯機場
祝你們旅途愉快
我需要你在這裡簽名
I just need your signature please.
- 你要住兩周嗎?  - 是的 女士
- You are with us for two weeks?  - Yes, ma'am.
謝謝
Thanks.
你的鑰匙 156房間
Here's your key. Room 156.
謝謝你 女士
Thank you, ma'am.
歡迎回來 貝克先生
Welcome back, Mr. Baker.
嘿
Hey.
噢 抱歉
Oh, pardon.
謝謝
Merci.
嘿 嘿
Hey. Hey.
你們介意小聲點嗎? 我想睡覺
Y'all mind keeping it down? I'm trying to sleep.
- 音樂  - 什麼?
- The music.  - Hein?
不懂英語
No-no English.
不會說英語
No speak English.
行 好吧
Yeah, all right.
嘿 晚安
Hey, good night.
- 你好  - 貝克
- Bonjour.  - Baker.
探視囚犯的授權
好了
薩利姆 九號
Salim, neuf.
穆薩 十號
Moussa, dix.
貝克 十一號
Baker, onze.
謝謝
Merci.
- 嘿 甜心  - 嘿 爸爸
- Hey, baby girl.  - Hey, Dad.
你看起來不錯
You look good.
謝謝
Thanks.
旅途怎麼樣?
How was the flight?
還行
Okay.
你還好嗎?
You doing all right?
- 我很好 是啊  - 好
- I'm okay, yeah.  - Good.
好 你有要洗的衣服嗎?
Good. You got some laundry for me?
有 有一些
Yeah. Some.
我會拿去洗
I'll get it done.
他們給了我們兩次探視時間
They gave us two more visiting days.
下次是 星期五下午2點
The next one's, uh, Friday, 2:00 p.m.
外婆怎麼樣?
How's Gram?
她很好
She's good.
一直在吸氧
Still got the oxygen tank.
她還是很嘮叨
Still got plenty of opinions.
想她
Miss her.
她給你買了你想要的東西
She bought you everything you wanted.
嗯 給你多買了一雙襪子
Uh, we got you a extra pair of socks
還有雙不錯的新運動鞋
and, uh, good new pair of sneakers.
謝謝
Thanks.
呃 外婆說她有照片要你帶給我
Uh, Gram said that she was giving you some photos for me.
啊 該死 我忘帶了
Ah, shit. I forgot them.
噢 下次帶來吧
Oh, just bring them next time.
不 我是說我把它們忘在靜水的家裡了
No, I mean I forgot them at home in Stillwater.
很抱歉
Sorry.
沒事
Doesn't matter.
我在機場給你買了件牛仔隊的運動衫
I got you, uh, a Cowboys sweatshirt at the airport.
他們今年表現不錯
They're gonna be good this year.
他們有個從格思裡來的OL近端鋒
They got this big ol' tight end out of Guthrie.
OL: 美式足球中由5名球員組成的攻擊鋒線
要三個人才能防住他
Takes about three guys to bring him down.
他肯定會進職業聯賽
He gonna go pro for sure.
很棒
Cool.
你還在圖書館工作嗎?
You still working at the library?
不 我辭職了
No, I quit.
爸爸 我要你幫我做件事
Um, Dad, I need you to do something.
你把它交給萊帕克
I need you to get that to Leparq,
一定要讓她看到
make sure she reads it.
- 好嗎?  - 這是什麼?
- Okay?  - Wh-What is it?
是封信 一定交給她
It's-it's a letter. Just give it to her.
- 行 好的  - 地址在信封上 好嗎?
- Yeah, yeah.  - The-the address is on the envelope, okay?
行 好的
Yeah, okay.
你沒事吧?
But are you good?
爸爸 拜託
Dad, please.
我今天就去送
I'll do it today.
保證讓她看到
I'll make sure she reads it.
好
Okay.
我們祈禱下好嗎?
Mind if we pray a bit?
當然 爸爸
Yeah, sure, Dad.
感謝主
Thank you, Lord,
您在這蒙福的日子裡讓我們相聚
for bringing us together on this blessed day and
感謝您一直守護著艾莉森
thank you for keeping a watchful eye on Allison.
貝克先生
Mr. Baker.
抱歉讓你久等 但萊帕克律師
I'm sorry you had to wait, but Maitre Leparq
今天不回辦公室了
is not coming back to the office today.
那我明天再來 謝謝你 女士
I'll come back tomorrow, then. Thank you, ma'am.
貝克先生 她整個星期都得出庭
Mr. Baker, she's in court all week.
你為什麼不把信給我
Why don't you give me your letter
我會轉交給她的
and I will make sure she gets it.
不麻煩了 謝謝你 女士
Can't do that. Thank you, ma'am.
你請便
As you wish.
- 你好  - 嘿
- Bonjour.  - Hey.
你被鎖在外面了?
You locked out?
什麼?
Quoi?
門卡 你有門卡嗎?
Key. You got a key?
啊 呃 沒有
Ah, euh, non.
來吧 我們去拿
Come on, let's go get it.
來吧 我給你拿張新門卡
Come on. I'm gonna get you a new key.
貝爾?
Bell?
比爾
Bill.
必爾?
Beal?
差不多
Closer.
你叫什麼名字?
What's your name?
- 什麼?  - 你
- Hmm?  - You.
瑪雅
Maya.
瑪雅 好聽的名字
Maya. Ah, that's nice.
這是什麼?
CC'est quoi?
是個紋身
It's a tattoo.
嗯?
Hmm?
噢 是一隻鷹
Oh, it's a eagle.
- 鷹?  - 鷹
- Eagle?  - Eagle.
白頭鷹 象徵美國
Bald eagle. America.
對 還有個骷髏 上面交叉插著刀
Yeah, and I got a skull with a knife going through it.
- 謝謝  - 謝謝你 女士
- Merci.  - Thank you, ma'am.
謝謝
Merci.
Thank you.
下午好 我在找個人 萊帕克律師
Afternoon. I'm looking for, uh, for that person, Maitre Leparq.
萊帕克女士?
Ms. Leparq?
- 貝克先生?  - 是的 女士
- Mr. Baker?  - Yes, ma'am.
我只佔用你幾分鐘的時間
I just need a few minutes of your time.
我女兒的信
Letter from my daughter.
抱歉 貝克先生
I'm sorry, Mr. Baker,
我不能答應你女兒的請求
but I cannot honor your daughter's request.
為什麼?
Why's that?
貝克先生 法官不會因為傳聞就重審這個案子
Mr. Baker, a judge will not reopen this case based on hearsay.
這不可能
This is not possible.
好吧
Okay.
我們已試過一切可能的法律途徑了
We have exhausted every possible legal action.
這封信告訴我 你女兒
This letter tells me that your daughter
她沒有接受她的判決
has not accepted her sentence.
她必須接受
And she must.
你明白嗎?
Do you understand?
明白 女士
Yes, ma'am.
我得走了
I must go.
我整天都有事
I have a full day.
我能拿回那封信嗎?
Can I get that letter back?
拿去吧
As you wish.
- 謝謝  - 貝克先生
- Thank you.  - Mr. Baker,
有時我們應該懷有希望 但有時也應該接受現實
there's a time for hope and there's a time for acceptance.
你最不想給你女兒的就是虛假的希望
The last thing you want to give your daughter is false hope.
這可能會使她的處境變得更糟
That could make her situation very dire.
你明白嗎?
Do you understand?
是的 女士
Yes, ma'am.
你好
Hello.
嘿
Hey.
謝謝你昨天幫我女兒瑪雅
Uh, thank you for helping my daughter Maya yesterday.
我回來有點晚了
I was a little bit late coming back.
那個 呃 你知道 我們剛搬家
It's, uh, you know, we're between apartments,
我們的新家還沒有通電
and we don't have electricity at our new place.
所以...
So...
抱歉 我...
Sorry, I...
「我不會說英語」
I don't speak English.
噢 是的
Oh, yes.
包廂 對
The balcony. Yeah.
哦 好吧 我的英語又回來了
Um, well, my-my English came back to me.
呃 我很抱歉吵到你了
Uh, I'm-I'm sorry for the loud noise.
都怪我的朋友內吉瑪
It's because of my girlfriend Nedjma.
她對我影響不好
She's a bad influence on me.
我叫維吉妮
I'm, uh, Virginie.
我叫比爾
I'm Bill.
你好 比爾
Hello, Bill.
你在馬賽度假嗎?
You're in Marseille for vacation?
呃 看望我女兒
Uh, visiting my daughter.
那很好
It's cool.
好吧 希望我們只需在這裡待一兩天
Well, hopefully we're only here for one or two more days,
但如果你需要什麼 我們就在隔壁
but if you need anything, you know, we're next door.
謝謝你 女士
Thank you, ma'am.
謝謝你 再見 比爾
Thank you. Bye, Bill.
「親愛的萊帕克律師
"Dear Maitre Leparq,
「我寫信給你是因為帕特裡克·奧康內多博士
"I'm writing to you because I was contacted by
「聯繫了我
"Dr. Patrick Okonedo,
「呃 他是我大學時參加的
"uh, chief of the outreach program
「外展計劃負責人
"I was involved in at university.
「帕特裡克有個學生告訴他
"Patrick was approached by a student
「在一次聚會上遇到個叫阿基姆的人
"who met a guy named Akim at a party.
「阿基姆說他幾年前刺傷了一個女孩
"She was told he had stabbed a girl years ago
「並僥倖逃脫了
"and got away with it.
阿基姆肯定是殺了莉娜的那個人」
It must be the same Akim who killed Lina."
你是那個美國女學生的父親嗎?
You're the father of the girl, the-the American student?
是的 女士
Yes, ma'am.
呃...
Um...
「他的DNA必須與犯罪現場
"H-His DNA must be compared
「發現的未知DNA進行比較
"to the unknown DNA found on the crime scene.
「我 我請求你調查一下
"I, uh, I beg you to investigate,
「去跟奧科內多先生和那個學生談談
"to talk to Mr. Okonedo and to the student.
「我是無辜的
"I am innocent of this crime,
「沒有其他人能幫我了
"and I have no one else to assist me.
「我的外婆沒法再來馬賽
"My grandmother can no longer make the trips to Marseille,
「你也知道我父親
"and you know my father.
「我不相信他能處理好這事
"I cannot trust him with this.
「他沒什麼能力
"He's not capable.
「請不要把我扔在這個可怕的地方
"Please do not abandon me in this horrible place.
「我已經失去了五年生命
"I have lost five years of my life,
「而且還會失去四年
"and I still have four to go.
真誠的艾莉森·貝克」
Sincerely, Allison Baker."
很抱歉
I'm sorry.
謝謝你幫忙
Appreciate your help.
請不要對任何人說這件事
Please don't say anything to anybody about this.
是的 當然
Oui, bien sur.
貝克先生 這邊請
Mr. Baker. Please, this way.
那麼 我能幫你些什麼?
So, how can I help you?
好吧 我想和萊帕克律師談談這案子
Well, I want to see Mrs. Leparq about the case.
萊帕克律師今天不在
Maitre Leparq is not available today.
有新的線索
There's a new lead.
有個人...
This guy...
在一次聚會上提到謀殺案
was talking at a party about the murder.
- 貝克先生...  - 所以有人需要和那個老師談談
- Mr. Baker...  - So somebody needs to talk to this teacher,
他叫帕特裡克·奧科內多
this guy, Patrick Okonedo.
我們需要聽聽他說的
We need to hear what he has to say.
貝克先生 萊帕克律師昨天跟你說得很清楚
Mr. Baker, Maitre Leparq was very clear with you yesterday.
她不能再跟蹤這案子了
She cannot pursue this case.
但如果你想進一步調查
But if you wish to pursue a further investigation,
我們可以推薦這個
we can recommend this.
這是一份你可以僱傭的私家偵探名單
It's a list of private detectives you can engage.
不 我不想要 我不想要偵探
No, I don't want, I don't want a detective.
我們和名單上的人一起工作過
We have worked with the people on this list,
他們都很能幹
and they're all very capable.
我不在乎他們有多能幹 我不想...
I don't care how capable they are. I don't want...
- 我圈出那些你能...  - 別圈了
- I'm circling the names that you can...  - Stop circling that.
我女兒還在該死的監獄裡
My daughter's in fucking jail.
我不需要該死的名單
I don't need some fucking list.
呃 你沒事吧?
Euh, ca va?
是的 我沒事
Oui, oui, ca va, oui.
謝謝
Merci.
隨你的便
As you want.
去他的
Fuck this.
謝謝 西比爾
Merci, Sybille.
- 嘿  - 你好
- Hey. Mm.  - Hi.
- 你還好嗎?  - 是啊 我很好
- You good?  - Yeah, I'm good, I'm good.
今天讓你出來晚了 他們不該那麼做
Let you out a bit late today. They shouldn't do that.
你知道他們會準時叫你回去的
You know they're gonna call you back in on time.
沒關係 這時有發生
It's okay. It happens sometimes.
- 我幫你洗了衣服  - 謝謝
- I did your laundry.  - Thanks.
嗯 你把我的信給萊帕克了嗎?
Um, did you give my letter to Leparq?
當然給了
Yeah, of course.
她說了什麼?
And what'd she say?
她告訴我你寫的有關阿基姆和派對上那個女孩的事
Well, uh, she told me what you wrote about Akim and the girl at the party.
她說了什麼?
And what'd she say?
她說 你知道
Well, she said, you know,
她處理過很多這樣的案子...
she works on a lot of these cases...
爸爸
Dad.
她到底要不要調查?
Is she gonna investigate it or not?
告訴我
Just tell me.
會 她會調查的
Yeah, she's gonna look into it.
真的?
Really?
她這麼說的?
She said that?
她說她會調查嗎?
She said she's gonna look into it?
沒錯
That's right.
我告訴她你對這個很有信心
I told her how strongly you felt about it.
- 她需要我做什麼嗎?  - 不
- Does she need me to do anything?  - No.
她說她需要一些時間 而且 呃...
No. She said she just needs some time, and, uh...
她確實說過 她不想作出任何承諾
She did say, uh, she didn't want to make any promises.
她不想給你任何虛假的希望
She-she didn't want to give you any false hope
- 或許不是那樣  - 不 不 不 但那仍然很好
- or nothing like that.  - No, no, no, no, no. But that's-that's still great.
阿基姆確實存在
Akim exists.
他殺了莉娜
He killed Lina.
我知道
I know.
我知道那個
I know that.
你不知道那封信
You have no idea how many times
我 我反覆寫了多少遍
I-I wrote and then rewrote that letter.
噢 天哪
Oh, my God.
嗯 那封信管用了
Well, it worked.
對
Yeah.
也許上帝回應了我們的祈禱
Maybe God answered our prayers.
謝謝你 爸爸
Thank you, Dad.
非常感謝你
Thank you so much.
打擾下 女士
Excuse me, ma'am.
我叫比爾·貝克 來問一份名單
Bill Baker. Called about a list.
請稍等
One moment please.
我不知道這個案子你還
I don't know how much you remember
記得多少 但艾莉森是來上大學的
about the case, but Allison came here for college,
她就是在那裡認識了莉娜
and that's where she met this girl, Lina.
艾莉森和莉娜... 在一起
Allison and Lina were... together,
一天晚上她們大吵了一架 艾莉森去了酒吧
and one night they got in a big fight, and Allison went to a bar.
在那裡她遇到這個叫阿基姆的人
That's where she met this Akim guy.
他們喝了幾杯 他偷了她的錢包 然後...
And they had some drinks. He stole her purse, and...
當艾莉森回家時 發現莉娜已經死了
when Allison got home, she found Lina dead
她報了警
and called the police.
但警方從未找到這個阿基姆
And they never could find this Akim.
他是殺了莉娜的人
He's the one who killed Lina.
你怎麼認為?
What do you think?
嗯
Mm-hmm.
你會說英語 對吧?
You speak English, right?
英語?
English?
是 我會
Yes. I am.
媽的
Fuck.
把信還給我
Give me back the letter.
貝克先生
Mr. Baker.
請
Please.
我的辦公室
My office.
這個案子發生時我還是警察
I was in service at the time of this case.
在警局
In the police.
你和這個奧科內多談過了嗎?
Have you talked to this Okonedo?
- 這個教授  - 沒有 先生
- The professor.  - No, sir.
我明白你的律師為什麼不想幫忙了
I see why your lawyer doesn't want to help.
有個孩子在聚會上聽到關於謀殺的傳言
Some kid at a party hears gossip about a murder.
也許她還記得這個有名的案子
Maybe she remembers this famous case.
為什麼是現在? 那是五年前的事了
Why now? It was five years ago.
那是... 我女兒關在監獄的五年
That's... that's how long my kid's been in jail, five years.
她知道我們要見面嗎?
Does she know we are meeting?
你的女兒
Your kid.
不 先生
No, sir.
你有錢嗎 貝克先生?
Are you rich, Mr. Baker?
沒有 先生
No, sir.
這是個涉及DNA的案件
This is a DNA case.
這意味著有兩步
It means two steps.
首先 我要找那個年輕人
First, I look for the young man.
這並不容易
That will not be easy.
人們會談論此事 他聽到後會躲起來
People will talk. He will try to disappear.
如果我找到這個阿基姆
Then, if I find this Akim,
我必須獲取他的DNA樣本
I have to get a sample of his DNA
通過我在警察局的關係來與
and use my connections in the police to test it
犯罪現場的DNA進行對比
against the DNA from the crime scene.
多少錢?
How much?
1萬2千美元?
$12,000?
歐元
Euros.
謝謝你抽空見我
Thank you for your time.
貝克先生
Mr. Baker.
你相信你女兒是無辜的嗎?
Do you believe your daughter is innocent?
我相信
I know she is.
那這點錢與她能獲得自由比起來並不算多
Then maybe it's not so much to see her go free.
美國鷹 比爾
親愛的比爾  很高興認識你
祝你在馬賽好運
維吉妮和瑪雅
帕特裡克·奧科內多
- 打擾下 女士  - 什麼?
- Excuse me, ma'am.  - Yes?
- 能問你個問題嗎?  - 當然可以
- Ask you a question, please?  - Yes, of course.
我太笨了 一個人沒法解決這個問題
I'm just too much of a dumbass to figure this out on my own.
我不會說法語
I don't speak French.
我能幫你什麼嗎?
Uh, how can I help you?
我在找一個人
I'm looking for a guy,
艾克斯 - 馬賽大學
在這裡工作的
uh, who works here.
...人類世 提出人是驅動力...
- 有事嗎?  - 抱歉打擾了
- Oui?  - Sorry to interrupt.
你會說英語嗎?
Do you speak English?
我會
I do.
我在找帕特裡克·奧科內多
Looking for Patrick Okonedo.
你找到他了
請坐
Have a seat please.
沒事 我在外面等
That's all right. I'll wait outside.
不 不 請加入派對
No, no, please. Join the party.
來啊
而這個新時代伴隨著資源的枯竭...
...強烈的氣候不穩定和生物圈的退化...
...由於預期壽命延長的加速...
令人印象深刻 是嗎?
It's impressive, huh?
這是博士學位帶給我的辦公室
It's the kind of office a PhD will get you.
薄荷茶
Mint tea.
我想和你告訴艾莉森的那個派對女孩談談
I want to talk to the girl you told Allison about from the party.
是的 我也猜到了
Yes. I assumed as much.
老實說 我一直對發生的事情感到內疚
To be honest, I've always felt guilty about what happened.
我應該警告艾莉森的
I should've warned Allison.
警告她? 關於什麼?
Warned her? About what?
我知道艾莉森和莉娜在一起
Well, I knew Allison and Lina were sleeping together,
但我不知道莉娜已經搬去和她住了
but I had no idea Lina had moved in with her.
我盡量不對這種關係感到悲觀...
I try to not be cynical about these type of relationships...
貧民區的窮女孩和富有的美國學生...
poor girl from the ghetto, rich American student...
但我最終還是犯了天真的錯誤
but then I end up being guilty of naivete.
艾莉森是在貧窮中長大的
Allison grew up poor.
她並不富有
She isn't rich.
但她受過教育
Educated.
這裡的人對文化精英有諸多不滿情緒
There is a lot of resentments towards the cultural elite.
但我相信你知道這一點
But I'm sure you're aware of that.
派對上的那個女孩呢?
What about the girl from the party?
- 我的學生?  - 對
- My student?  - Yeah.
她叫蘇雅德
Her name is Souad.
她來自外展計劃
She's from the outreach program,
就是莉娜和艾莉森見面時參加的那個計劃
the same one Lina and Allison were involved with when they met.
她聽到有人說莉娜被謀殺了嗎?
And she heard some guy talking about Lina's murder?
這是她告訴我的
This is what she told me.
我能和她談談嗎?
Could I talk to her?
她會跟你說的 是的
She'll talk to you, yes.
我把她的電話號碼給你
I'll give you her phone number.
蘇雅德英語說得不太好
Souad doesn't speak English very well.
你需要有人翻譯
You will need someone to translate.
噢 你能幫我嗎?
Oh, could you do that for me?
不 我不想這麼做
No, I'd rather not.
我還在執行外展計劃
I'm still running the outreach program.
發生這些事後 我不能和你
I cannot be associated with you.
或者你的女兒扯上關係
Or your daughter, after what happened.
再說我個人的意見並不重要
Whatever my personal opinion may be.
我女兒是無辜的
My daughter's innocent.
祝你好運
I wish you good luck.
嘿 帕特裡夏 恐怕我又需要幫助了
Hey, Patricia, afraid I need some help again.
我明天要參加一個特別的生日聚會
I'm supposed to attend a very special birthday tomorrow,
我把地址弄丟了
and I lost the address.
你好?
Bonjour?
嗨 我是比爾·貝克
Hi. It's Bill Baker.
什麼?
Pardon?
- 比爾 酒店的  - 啊 比爾
- Bill, from the hotel.  - Ah, Bill.
對 我順道過來 抱歉...
Yeah, I was stopping by. Sorry to...
- 呃 在頂樓  - 好的
- Uh, last floor.  - All right.
嗨 比爾
Hi, Bill.
嘿 瑪雅
Hey, Maya.
我有東西給你
I got something for you.
一個機器人
It's a robot.
機器人! 媽媽 比爾給我買了一個機器人!
- 我可以打開嗎?  - 當然
- 嗨  - 嗨 抱歉打擾了
- Hi.  - Hi. Sorry to intrude.
不 沒關係 進來吧
No, it's okay. Come in.
呃 我有一些朋友過來了
Um, I have some friends over.
噢
Oh.
你是怎麼找到這裡的?
How did you find us?
噢 接待處的女士給了我你的地址
Oh, the lady at reception gave me your address
因為我要給這個女孩打電話
'cause there's this girl I need to call,
但她不會說英語 這個是私事
but she don't speak English, and it's kind of personal.
啊 你想讓我幫你打電話 對嗎?
Ah, you want me to make the call for you. Is that right?
是的 女士 但我下次再來
Yes, ma'am, but I'll come back another time.
不 沒事 進來吧
No, it's fine. Uh, just come in.
我去拿手機
Just let me grab my phone.
來
Come.
各位 這是比爾
嘿
Hey.
比爾 他們是
Bill, this is, uh,
馬賽戲劇界的精英
the creme de la crme of the Marseille theater scene.
- 暫停五分鐘  - 是休息還是什麼?
是的
Ouais.
我們在做這個 呃 面具練習
Uh, we're doing this, uh, mask exercise.
- 好吧  - 是啊
- All right.  - Yeah.
不好意思很亂
Excuse the mess.
這是我的辦公室 但我們還沒搬進來
This is going to be my office, but we're still moving in.
請坐
Have a seat.
那麼 給誰打電話?
So, who am I calling?
呃...
Um...
信裡那個女孩
the girl from the letter.
- 是關於這個案子的嗎?  - 是的 女士
- Ah, it's about the case?  - Yes, ma'am.
我想見見她
I want to meet with her.
律師沒有幫你嗎?
Is the lawyer not helping you?
呃 現在我自己在辦
Uh, doing it myself for now.
噢 哇
Oh. Wow.
好吧...
Okay. Um...
瑪雅 請把燈打開 親愛的
- 好的  - 嗯...
- Oui.  - Um...
- 燈又壞了  - 又壞了?
- 是的 你看  - 天啊
便宜沒好事 我通過一個朋友
What a great deal, I got this place
買了這個地方
through this friend of mine.
我喜歡這個景色 但還是有些缺憾
I fell in love with this view, but, uh, has a few defects.
可能是斷路器的問題
Probably just a circuit breaker.
如果你願意 我可以看看
I could look at it if you want.
- 嗯 你知道怎麼修嗎?  - 是的 女士
- Yeah. You know how to do that?  - Yes, ma'am.
喔 那太好了
Well, that would be great.
蘇雅德? 蘇雅德?
Souad? Souad?
你好 蘇雅德?
Oui, bonjour. Souad?
你好
Bonjour.
...比爾·貝克
...Bill Baker.
比爾·貝克...
Bill Baker...
噢 不
Oh, non.
機器人的腳掉了下來
我看看 我看看
Let me see. Let me see.
- □ 嘿  - 好
- □ Hey  - Cool.
□ 性感女士... □
□ Sexy lady... □
我不知道它還能唱歌
I didn't know it did that.
媽媽 我的機器人已經壞了
媽媽在打電話
這很容易 等一下 好了
That-that goes on easy. Hold on. There you go.
噢 一個不能站立的機器人有什麼用?
看起來不錯
Looks good.
謝謝你
Merci beaucoup.
再見
Au revoir.
好了 她同意明天6點見你
Okay. She agrees to see you tomorrow at 6:00.
好吧
All right.
嗯 她人很好
Um, she was nice.
有點害羞
Bit shy.
如果你不會說法語 你怎麼跟她交談?
So how are you gonna talk to her if you don't speak French?
哦 這是個好問題
Well, that's a fair question.
我會想法解決
I'll figure it out.
好吧
Okay.
如果你需要的話 我可以來翻譯
Well, I could come and translate if you need.
你確定?
You sure?
嗯 是的
Uh, yeah.
明天瑪雅有藝術課 如果你5點半來這裡
Yeah, Maya has art class, so if you come here at 5:30,
可以坐我的車去
then we take my car.
謝謝你
Appreciate it.
你告訴我保險絲盒在哪裡
Uh, you show me where that fuse box is,
我來幫你修那個斷路器
I'll work on that breaker for you.
不 沒事
No, it's okay.
你不用那麼做
You don't have to do that.
噢 不 不
Oh, non, non.
一隻胳膊和一條腿又掉下來了
把那該死的東西給我 我來
Just give me that damn thing. I... Come on.
比爾
Bill!
再見 比爾
Bye, Bill!
再見
Bye.
我必須承認 我在網上看了艾莉森的案子
I have to confess, uh, I went online and I read about Allison's case.
這在當時是個大新聞
It was a big story at the time.
我是說 媒體的表現很惡毒 不是嗎?
I mean, the-the press was ferocious, no?
你們說的「惡毒」?
Y-You say "f-ferocious"?
- 是的 女士 我們是這麼說的  - 是嗎?
- Yes, ma'am, we say that.  - Yeah?
媽的
Putain.
笨蛋
Dumbass.
是啊 在這個該死的城市 人們...
Yeah, people... they don't know how to drive
不知道如何開車
in this fucking town.
馬賽是個瘋狂的地方
It's a crazy place, Marseille.
但我還是覺得比巴黎好
But I still prefer it to Paris.
知道嗎 這裡的人至少還互相交流
You know, people actually talk to each other here.
而且 生活更便宜
And plus, it's cheaper.
艾莉森為什麼來這裡上學?
And why did Allison come here for school?
我很好奇
I'm curious.
- 不知道  - 不知道?
- Don't know.  - No?
對 她本來要上俄克拉荷馬州立大學
Yeah, she was going to Oklahoma State.
有一天她打來電話給我說
She just called me up one day, said,
「我要去法國」 去這兒
"I'm going to France," to here.
她很獨立
She's independent.
是的 女士 一直都是
Yes, ma'am. Always been.
你們關係好嗎?
Are you close?
哦 你看過她的信了
Well, you read her letter.
她媽媽在哪裡?
And where is her mother?
她死了
She passed.
是自殺的
Killed herself.
艾莉森大部分是由她的祖母撫養長大的
Allison was raised by her grandmother mostly.
我不常在家
I wasn't around much.
你在哪裡?
Where were you?
在石油平台工作...
Working oil rigs and...
我沒上班時也很忙
being a fuckup when I wasn't.
單親爸爸並不容易
It's not easy being a single parent.
我經常在晚上工作 瑪雅也很不高興
I often work at night, and Maya, she gets really upset.
- 你是做什麼的?  - 我是演員
- What do you do?  - I'm an actress.
- 噢 演電視的?  - 不
- Oh, on TV?  - No.
在劇院
Theater.
你去過劇院嗎?
Do you go to theater?
沒有 女士
No, ma'am.
- 從沒有?  - 沒有 女士
- Never?  - No, ma'am.
好吧
Okay.
謝謝你們和我談話
Uh, thank y'all for talking to me.
她在派對上遇到的那個人 阿基姆...
So, this guy that she met at the party, Akim...
她能告訴我們有關他的任何事嗎?
uh, anything she could tell us about him?
她說他很文靜而且人很好
She said he was quiet and nice.
很好?
Nice?
他告訴她的朋友他刺傷過一個女孩
And then he told her friend he'd stabbed a girl
而且警察從未抓到他
and that the police never caught him.
- 所以...  - 好吧
- So...  - Okay.
她知道他住在哪裡嗎?
Does she know where he lives?
- 她是誰? 他的老婆?  - 不 我是他的朋友
我不是在和你說話
她知道他住在哪裡嗎?
Does she know where he lives?
- 在卡利斯特  - 卡利斯特?
- AA Kalliste.  - Kalliste?
她說他住在一個不同的住所
She says he lives in a different project.
那裡叫卡利斯特
It's called Kalliste.
- 不要給我惹麻煩  - 我沒有
我住在那裡! 我們不認識他們! 媽的閉嘴!
你怎麼知道她不是警察?
- 不 我只是想幫我朋友  - 我已經告訴過你我不是在和你說話
- 她在說什麼?  - 沒什麼幫助
- What's she saying?  - Nothing helpful.
我是 呃... 父親
I-I'm, uh... le pere.
呃 艾莉森
Uh, Allison.
是我的女兒
That's my little girl.
艾莉森是我的... 女兒
Allison is my... ma fille.
你明白嗎?
You understand?
給你的朋友解釋一下 這就是馬賽的情況
這裡的人喜歡談各種八卦
我們什麼都不知道 告訴她
她不想幫我們
She doesn't want to help.
她能告訴我什麼嗎?
Can she tell me anything?
這傢伙長什麼樣?
Wh-What does this guy look like?
你不明白嗎? 你讓我抓狂 我已經告訴過你了 我們不是告密者 我們走
- 他們要去哪裡?  - 他們要走了
- Where they going?  - They're leaving.
不 不 不 等等 等等 等等
Uh, no, no, no. Hold on, hold on, hold on, hold on.
等等 不 等等 等等 不 不
Wait, no, no. Hold on. Just wait. No, no.
你在做什麼? 放開我朋友 別碰我朋友
- 好吧 好吧  - 喔 喔 喔
- All right, all right.  - Wouah, wouah, wouah! Wouah!
沒事 沒事 走 走
蘇雅德 嘿 蘇雅德 蘇雅德
Souad. Hey, Souad! Souad!
比爾 比爾 讓他們走 好嗎? 她很害怕
Bill, Bill, let them go, okay? She's afraid.
怕什麼? 我只是和她說話
Afraid of what? I'm talking to her.
對 但這種方式行不通
Yeah, but that's not how it works here.
那麼你告訴我怎麼做才行
Well, you tell me how it works then,
因為這裡沒人幫我
'cause nobody here's doing shit for me.
我在幫你 好嗎?
I do shit for you, okay?
我們該走了 馬上
We should go. Now.
好嗎?
Okay?
- 行 好吧  - 好了?
- Yeah, all right.  - All right?
那就是 卡利斯特
That's it. Kalliste.
她說阿基姆就住在那裡
That's where she says Akim lives.
我們可以四處看看嗎?
Well, can we go look around?
不 現在不行
No. Not at this time.
對我們來說不安全
It's not safe for us.
因為我們是白人?
'Cause we're white?
因為我們不是這裡的
'Cause we're not from there.
這裡有很多毒品交易
And there's a lot of dealing.
好吧 我得做點什麼
Well, I got to do something.
相信我 沒人會跟你說的
No one will talk to you, trust me.
比爾 如果這裡沒有阿基姆呢?
Bill, what if there's no Akim?
這裡有
There is.
好吧 但他們在調查期間沒找到這個人
Okay, but they never found this person during the investigation.
我女兒不會說謊
My daughter's not a liar.
不 我不是說她撒謊
No, I didn't say she was.
只是我瞭解的關於這個案子的一切都...
It's just that everything I read about the case...
所以你現在是專家了?
So you're some kind of expert now?
不 我不是
No, I'm not.
媒體不支持我們
The press was against us.
他們關心的只是
All they cared about was
艾莉森和一個阿拉伯女孩上床了
Allison was sleeping with some Arab girl.
一群...
Bunch of...
假新聞混蛋
fake news scumbags.
所以你打了那個英國記者?
That's why you punched that English reporter?
我當時喝多了
I was drinking then.
嘿 你有沒有告訴外婆關於萊帕克的事?
Hey, did you tell Gram about Leparq?
沒有
No.
在我們有更多證據前 我不想讓她抱有希望
No, I didn't want to get her hopes up until we know more.
你外婆 她正在康復期間
She's getting on, your grandmother.
噢 我昨天和法官見過面
Oh, I had a meeting with the judge yesterday.
是嗎? 說了什麼?
Oh, yeah? About what?
大約三個月後開始我的假釋審核
Well, I have my parole review coming up in about three months.
就是說我一個月可以出去一天
And, uh, it's the thing where I get out of here one day a month.
是啊 好
Yeah, okay.
- 他說了什麼?  - 是她 她說
- So what'd he say?  - She. She said.
知道嗎 只要我保持行為良好
Uh, you know, as long as my behavior remained good,
審核應該沒問題
shouldn't be a problem.
我心裡在說 「去他的假釋
I felt like saying, "Fuck parole.
我的律師正在想法讓我永遠離開這裡」
My lawyer's working on getting me out of here for good."
不 還不知道會怎樣 艾莉
No, we don't know that yet, Ally.
- 你必須保持...  - 我知道 知道 爸爸
- You got to keep...  - I know, I know, I know, Dad.
我不會那麼說 只是那麼想
I-I didn't say that. But I wanted to.
而且... 萊帕克辦公室的人來過
And... somebody from Leparq's office was there.
噢 是嗎?
Oh, yeah?
是的 我從未見過她 但我問過她
Yeah. I never met her, but I asked her
調查進展怎麼樣了
how the investigation was going.
她跟你說了什麼?
What'd she tell you?
她說她對這個案子一無所知
She said she didn't know anything about it,
但她也說她剛到那裡工作
but she also said she just started working there.
萊帕克可能自己在處理
Leparq's probably taking care of it herself.
這是個大案
It's a big case.
對
Yeah.
我告訴她我想和萊帕克談談
I told her I wanted to talk to Leparq.
她應該讓我們瞭解進展
She should be keeping us informed.
- 你明白我意思嗎?  - 我會和她談的
- You know what I mean?  - I'll talk to her.
時間到
好吧 那麼...
Okay. Well...
過幾天再見
I'll see you in a couple days.
爸爸 你覺得你能留在馬賽久一些嗎?
Uh, Dad, do you think that you could stay in Marseille a little longer?
萬一有事要處理
Just in case something comes up.
行 沒問題
Yeah, I could do that.
我可以去找個事做
I'll check in on work and stuff.
如果你需要的話 我讓外婆匯些錢給你
I-I can have Gram wire you some money if you need.
不 不 別那麼做 我會想辦法
No, no, don't do that. I-I'll figure it out.
謝謝 爸爸
Thanks, Dad.
再見
Bye.
呃 馬克斯
Uh, Max.
你好
Salut.
就是這些 你有所有工具
你可以用它們 用完後放回去就行了
這是配電盤
- 那裡是什麼?  - 那很危險
明白了嗎?
- 明白了  - 好
- D'accord.  - Ay.
一旦石油公司有了租約...
Now, once the oil company has a lease...
遞給我 瑪
Give it here, M.
快點
Come on.
一旦石油公司有了租約
Once that oil company has that lease,
他們就雇一家鑽井公司
they hire a drilling company.
就是我工作的那家
That's who I work for.
然後我們到了那裡 安裝設備
And then we get there, we rig up
把所有東西都裝配起來
and we put all that shit together.
一旦我們安裝好設備
Once we have that rig up,
就開始鑽井
we start making hole.
這就是一個鑽工所做的
That's what a roughneck does.
我們鑽井
We make hole.
好吧 來試試
All right, test it.
去吧 沖一下
Go on, flush it.
按一下
Get it.
- 沖洗  - 啊 沖洗
- Flush.  - Ah, flush.
- 對  - 同意
- Yeah.  - D'accord.
沖洗
Flush.
- 好了嗎?  - 沒錯 好了
- CCa va?  - Hell yeah, ca va!
比爾 來
Bill, come.
過來
Come here.
來看看這個
Come and see this.
內吉瑪是個技術天才
Nedjma is a technical genius.
我不是天才 我只是年輕些
I'm not a genius. I'm just younger.
- 你只比我小三歲  - 這就是關鍵
- 好吧...  - 這些照片是在線的還是什麼?
- Okay...  - These are online or some shit?
都是蘇雅德和她那偏執朋友
These are all from Instagram accounts
的INS賬戶裡面的
of Souad and her bitchy friend.
這些照片都是派對上的
And these photos are all from the party.
你們怎麼弄到的?
How'd y'all get them?
我開設了一個假的INS賬戶
I set up a false Instagram account,
關注了蘇雅德和她漂亮的朋友薩米拉
followed Souad and her lovely friend whose name is Samira,
然後給蘇雅德看到這傢伙的派對進行地理標注
and then geotagged the party Souad was at when she saw this guy.
那麼阿基姆就有可能出現在其中一張照片中
So there's a chance Akim is in one of these photos.
- 我們怎麼找?  - 他說他很高...
...阿拉伯人和淺膚色
...Arab and light skin.
對 淺膚色 是的 而且很高
Yeah, uh, light skin, yeah, and tall.
他說「淺膚色」是什麼意思?
如果那沒有任何意思 我是什麼?
你在瞎說啥
所以我們要把照片打印出來
So we're going to print them up,
然後你拿去給艾莉森看
and then you can show them to Allison.
- 不 我不會那麼做  - 為什麼?
- No, I'm not gonna do that.  - Why?
如果阿基姆在那裡 她會認出的
If Akim is there, she'll know.
我不在乎
I don't care.
我不會那麼做 我不會那樣對她
I'm not gonna do that. I'm not gonna do it to her.
我得保護她
I got to protect her.
我不明白
I don't understand.
為什麼你在艾莉森這事上這麼固執?
Wh-why you're being so stubborn about Allison?
現在我們有了這些照片
What we should do is go back to Souad
應該再去找蘇雅德
now we got those pictures.
我們是從INS偷的這些照片
Well, we stole these photos from Instagram,
所以我不確定這是個好主意
so I'm not sure this is a good idea.
- 哦...  - 我能說點什麼嗎?
- Well...  - Can I say something?
當然 請說
Ouais, vas-y.
在馬賽除了艾莉森還有人見過這個阿基姆嗎?
Did anyone else in Marseille see this Akim guy or just Allison?
酒吧老闆
Bar owner.
他們相遇的地方
Where they met.
他參加了審判
He was at the trial.
- 但他什麼都沒做...  - 好吧
- He didn't do shit, but...  - Okay.
那裡叫什麼? 酒吧叫什麼名字?
Uh, what's it called, the bar? What's the name?
我不記得它的名字了
I don't remember the name of it.
- 就在她的公寓附近  - 行 好吧
- It was near her apartment.  - Yeah. Okay.
- 嗯  - 嗯
- Mm.  - Mm.
所以這是你的新事業
你做到了零浪耗 難民 現在是他
別說了 拜託
什麼? 你就承認喜歡他吧 那是你奇怪的愛好
- 夠了  - 那就問問他
我告訴過你 這不重要
好吧
Okay.
比爾 你投票給特朗普了嗎?
Bill, did you vote for Trump?
沒有
No.
啊 哇啦
Ah. Voila.
- 我沒有投票  - 什麼?
- I didn't vote.  - What?
- 你為什麼不投票?  - 我有記錄
- Why didn't you vote?  - Got a record.
我被捕過
I was arrested.
這種情況他們不會讓你投票的
They don't let you vote when that happens.
太好了 他受到了懲罰
祝你好運 你會需要它
就在那裡 在那個拐角處
It's there, around that corner.
你的朋友 內吉瑪...
Your friend, uh, Nedjma...
她因為你幫我而生你的氣?
she mad at you for helping me?
別擔心內吉瑪 她總是咄咄逼人
Don't worry about Nedjma, she's generally hostile.
知道嗎 她是想保護我
You know, she's very protective with me,
她是個好朋友
but she's a good friend.
她幫我照看瑪雅
She helps me with Maya.
瑪雅的父親在哪裡?
Where's Maya's father?
在科西嘉島海灘經營一家夜總會
Corsica, running a nightclub on the beach.
他是個... 浪子
He was a... a fling.
- 你怎麼說這詞?  - 浪子 對的
- That's how you say?  - Fling, yeah.
好
Yeah.
他來看過你們嗎?
Does he visit?
他以前會來 但他不來會更好點
He used to, but it's better when he doesn't.
怎麼了?
What?
那是艾莉森住過的地方
That's where Allison lived.
二十一號
Twenty-one.
就是在那裡發生的?
That's where it happened?
對
Yeah.
- 你好  - 你好
- Bonjour.  - Bonjour.
- 打擾了 我在找這家酒吧的老闆  - 我就是
我們需要些信息 五年前你在這裡嗎?
不在 我們去年接手的這個地方
他是新主人
He's the new owner.
案發時他不在這裡
He wasn't there when the crime happened.
他知道在哪裡能找到以前的老闆嗎?
Does he know where we could find the old owner?
是的 我知道
Yes, I know.
他正在那裡
He's right there.
享受我的收益
Drinking my profits.
你女兒的遭遇太可怕了
我還是不明白他們怎麼會把這麼可愛的女孩送進監獄
看看這些搗蛋鬼
呃...
Euhm...
- 他們中有見過的嗎? - 難以辨認 他們看起來都差不多
他認出誰了嗎?
He recognize anybody?
他們來這裡總是惹麻煩 就好像馬賽是他們的一樣
我們能專心看照片嗎 拜託
我們都是一樣的
你的問題和墨西哥人一樣 你也是入侵者
他在說什麼?
What's he saying?
請你仔細看一下照片好嗎?
聽著 你指出照片上你想要的那個人 我會說我認識他
一切都會得到解決 如有必要 我會在法庭上作證
等等 這很重要
看看這些 他們似乎都犯了什麼罪
媽的
Putain.
好吧 很好 我們走
Okay. CC'est bon. Let's go.
他說了什麼?
What'd he say?
沒什麼 他沒用
Nothing. He's useless.
謝謝你 白癡
再見 女士
嘿
Hey.
Hey!
嘿 怎麼了?
Hey! What happened?
抱歉 我只是... 我沒法再跟那傢伙說下去了
I'm sorry. I just, uh... I can't talk to that guy anymore.
他只是說些可怕的話
He was just saying some horrible things.
比如什麼?
Like what?
他只想把一個阿拉伯孩子關進監獄 你知道嗎?
Like he just wants to put an Arab kid in jail, you know?
他不在乎是哪個
He doesn't care which one.
就為這個?
That's it?
就為這個? 「就為這個」是什麼意思?
That's it? What do you mean, "That's it"?
他是種族主義者
He's a racist.
好吧 他是種族主義者
Okay, he's a racist.
我們必須繼續和他談
We still got to talk to him.
不 我不跟他談 不
No. I don't talk to him, no.
他可能知道些什麼
Well, he might know something.
不 他什麼都不知道
No, he doesn't know something!
比爾 我們不能把一個無辜的男孩送進監獄
Bill, we're not gonna send an innocent boy to jail.
我女兒是無辜的
My daughter is innocent.
什麼? 媽的 真不敢相信有這種對話
Quoi? Oh, putain. Can't believe this conversation.
那你是生活在某個華麗的世界裡 親愛的
Well, then y-you live in some fancy-ass world, honey,
因為我一直和這樣的人一起工作
'cause I work with guys like that all the time.
不 但這不重要 好嗎? 那是不對的
No, but it doesn't matter, okay? It's not right.
我沒說這對...
I'm not saying it's ri...
我只想讓我的女兒出獄
I'm trying to get my little girl out of jail.
這才是我所關心的
That's all I give a fuck about.
你現在聽起來很美國
And you sound very American right now.
好 我是
Good. I am.
是的 你也是這裡的外來者
Yeah, and you're also a stranger here.
你什麼都不明白 你知道嗎?
You don't understand shit. You know what?
拿上你的東西 做你想做的事 但我不參與了
貝克先生 請稍等
Mr. Baker, one moment please.
你有個留言
You have a message.
她說你需要更多的錢
She said you need more money
因為萊帕克重啟這個案子了?
because Leparq reopened the case?
我正在處理這個 莎倫
I'm dealing with it, Sharon.
- 處理什麼?  - 沒什麼
- Dealing with what?  - Nothing.
我是說 艾莉森讓我給她一封信
I mean, Allison told me to give her a letter.
我給她了 現在萊帕克正在調查
I did, and now Leparq's looking into it.
哦 她又在找阿基姆了嗎?
Well, i-is she looking for Akim again?
我 我... 我告訴過你我會處理的 莎倫
I'm-I'm... I told you I'm dealing with it, Sharon.
- 誰來為這事付錢?  - 沒人在說錢
- Who is gonna pay for this?  - Nobody's talking about money.
好嗎?
Okay?
比爾 你在喝酒嗎?
Bill, have you been drinking?
沒有
No.
聽著 莎倫 我是她父親
Listen, Sharon, I'm her father.
噢 天哪 比爾
Oh, my God, Bill.
你應該去看看 然後回家
You're supposed to visit and come home.
別把事搞砸了
Don't mess with this.
在這件事上你得相信我
Y-You're gonna need to trust me on this.
好了
That's it.
我要打電話給萊帕克
I'm gonna call Leparq.
不 別那麼做 莎倫
No, don't do that, Sharon.
莎倫
Sharon!
爸爸 發生什麼事了?
Dad, what is going on?
我和外婆談過了 她說你的表現很奇怪
I talked to Gram, she said that you're acting really weird.
好吧 我要你相信我 好嗎?
All right, I just need you to trust me, all right?
我要你看看這些照片
I need you to look at these pictures.
爸爸?
Dad?
爸爸...
Dad...
你喝過酒嗎?
are you drinking?
什麼? 不 從沒喝過
What? No, never.
你吃藥了?
Are you using?
艾莉 我受夠那玩意兒了 你知道的
Ally, I'm done with that shit. You know that.
現在 來吧 看看這些照片
Now, come on, look at these pictures.
這都他媽是些什麼? 萊帕克在哪裡?
Wh-What the fuck are these?! Where's Leparq?!
- 為什麼她不在這裡?  - 看看這些照片
- Wh-Why isn't she here?!  - Just look at the photos
如果你看到阿基姆 告訴我
and tell me if you see Akim!
我想他在裡面
I think he's in there.
拜託 寶貝
Please, baby.
拜託
Please.
拜託了
- 不 我沒看見他  - 好的 好吧 這還有
- No, I don't see him.  - Okay, all right. There's more.
還有更多
There's more.
天啊
Holy shit.
你看見他了嗎? 哪一個?
You see him? Which one?
是他
That's him.
是他 那是阿基姆
That's him. That's Akim.
你確定? 那就是那天晚上的那個人?
You're sure? That's the guy from that night?
爸爸 就是他
Daddy, that's him.
卡利斯特?
Kalliste?
你確定嗎?
對 呃 是的 那裡面
Yeah. Uh, oui. In there.
開進去吧
Just drive on in.
謝謝
Thank you.
打擾了 女士
Excuse me, ma'am.
女士 你以前見過那個人嗎?
Ma'am, you seen that guy before?
阿基姆?
Akim?
- 沒有  - 他住在這裡 沒見過?
- Non. Non.  - He lives, he lives here. No?
夫人 你以前見過他嗎? 阿基姆?
Ma'am, have you seen him before? Akim?
不好意思 先生
Excuse me, sir.
- 你以前見過那個人嗎?  - 沒有
- You seen that guy before?  - Non.
你呢? 你以前見過這個人嗎?
How about you? Have you seen this guy before?
沒有
Nan.
- 我在找他 阿基姆  - 沒見過
- Looking for him. Akim.  - No.
你認識他嗎? 阿基姆?
You know him? Akim?
不
Non.
打擾下
Excuse me.
你們都認識這個人嗎?
Y'all know this guy?
他? 阿基姆?
Him? Akim?
不...
Non...
你見過那個人嗎?
You ever seen that guy?
阿基姆?
Akim?
不 不 不 不
Non, non. Non, non, non.
這個人?
This guy?
不認識?
No?
嘿 你認識這個人嗎?
Hey. You know that guy?
就在這裡? 阿基姆?
Right there? Akim?
你認識他嗎?
You know him?
這個人 阿基姆 他住這裡嗎?
This guy, Akim, he lives here?
是啊
Yeah.
不 不
Non, non.
阿基姆... 怎麼了?
How about... Akim?
不 不
Non, non.
再見 牛仔
Bye-bye, cowboy.
遊客 你迷路了嗎?
你會說英語嗎?
You speak English?
如果您在找舊港 它不是這裡
嘿 你認識這個人嗎? 他叫阿基姆
Hey, you know this guy? This... His name's Akim.
他... 他住在這裡
He li... he lives here.
這是誰? 你的男朋友?
阿基姆?
Akim?
這個人住在這裡
The guy lives here.
就是那個賤人
- 他不會說法語   - 他會說英語
我說英語 你舔我的老二
I-I speak English. You suck my dick.
看 我會空手道 像這樣
- 你們在幹什麼? 玩真的還是什麼?   - 放鬆 放鬆
- 他的錯 他先動手  - 閉嘴
他是誰?
- 他給我們看一張照片  - 他肯定是個告密者
- 他在四處打聽  - 天啊
你認識他嗎?
- 不 我不認識  - 為什麼他有你的照片?
我不知道 我不認識他 我不知道怎麼回事
快點 離開這裡
- 帶他離開這裡  - 去哪兒?
去加油站 加油站
來吧
Allez!
- 這裡  - 謝謝
- Ici.  - Merci.
你好
Hi.
他們問我是否認識任何人
They asked me if I knew anybody.
你沒事吧?
Are you okay?
我看見他了
I saw him.
我看見阿基姆了
I saw Akim.
在卡利斯特
In Kalliste.
你告訴警察了嗎?
Did you tell the police?
那是我的機會
That was my chance.
你怎麼搞的?
What the fuck did you do?
我在幫你
I was trying to help.
告訴我你到底做了什麼 爸爸
Tell me exactly what you did, Dad.
爸爸
Dad.
她不想調查 艾莉
She wouldn't do it, Ally.
萊帕克不願再調查這案子
Leparq wouldn't look into the case.
噢 天哪
Oh, my God.
你他媽騙我
You fucking lied.
所有這些事
About all of it.
當然 你就這德行
Of course you did.
我找到他了 艾莉
I found him, Ally.
我找到阿基姆了
I found Akim.
那你為什麼不報警?
And why didn't you call the police?
為什麼?
Why?!
你讓他跑了
You let him get away!
那混蛋現在不見了
He's fucking gone now!
他消失了
He's fucking gone!
我覺得自己好傻 我太傻了
I feel so stupid. I feel so stupid.
你一直在騙我 一輩子都在騙我
You've always lied to me, my entire life, always!
我恨自己一直相信你
I hate myself for ever trusting you!
看守! 看守!
我要出去!
- 艾莉 聽我說  - 不
- Ally, listen to me.  - No!
不 不
No! No.
你毀了我的人生
You are done fucking up my life.
你明白嗎?
Do you get that?
明白嗎?
Do you?
你他媽離我遠點
Stay the fuck away from me.
四  個  月  後
比爾 比爾
Bill! Bill!
比爾
Bill.
嘿 各位
Hey, guys.
嗨 比爾
He, Bill.
是啊 我知道了
Yeah, I got it.
□ 別擔心汽油 □
□ Don't worry about gasoline □
□ 因為我們要搬家了 □
□ 'Cause we're moving □
□ 別擔心電視屏幕 □
□ Don't worry about the TV screen □
□ 因為我們要搬家了... □
□ 'Cause we're moving... □
□ 我是個浪子 □
□ I am the prodigal son □
□ 我就像一把上膛的槍回家 □
□ I come home just like a loaded gun □
□ 我會在地下六英尺的地方安息... □
□ I'll find rest when I'm six feet underground... □
- 嗨 比爾  - 我們怎麼做?
- He, Bill.  - How we doing?
今天在學校還好嗎?
How was school today? Good?
你完成了嗎?
You get it done?
好吧 來 我們走
All right, come on. Let's go.
好 我拿到了
Yeah, I got it.
給 我給你買的
Here. I got you that.
瑪雅 你得把這些都吃了
Maya, you got to eat the whole thing.
不 我更喜歡巧克力
我知道你在做什麼
I see what you're doing,
但是你也得吃麵包
but you got to eat the bread part, too.
是的 看 拿著這個 吃了它
噢 你要我把它吃了嗎?
Oh, you gonna pawn it off on me?
好吧
All right.
比爾
Bill.
呃... 錘子
Uh... un marteau.
是的 很好 錘子
Oui. Tres bien. Marteau.
- 錘子  - 錘子
- Hammer.  - Hammer.
呃... 鑿...
Uh... ciseau...
呃... 鑿什麼來著
Uh... ciseausomething.
- 木鑿  - 木鑿
- Ciseau a bois.  - Ciseau a bois.
帶「鑿」的詞太多了
That's a shitload of words for "chisel."
- 鑿子  - 進來 打開燈
- Chisel.  - Come on in. Get the light.
- 燈光  - 燈光
- Lumiere.  - Lumiere.
瑪雅 吃晚飯了
Maya, supper.
瑪雅
Maya.
等等 他們就要開門了
那個禿子要輸了
That bald guy's gonna lose his shirt.
噢 不
Oh, non.
是的 他們就是這樣做的
Yeah, that's how they do it.
在大揭曉前就切換到廣告
Cut to commercial before the big reveal.
來 我們去吃飯
Come on, let's eat.
來吧
Come on.
你做作業了嗎?
You do your homework?
- 家庭作業?  - 啊 沒有
- Homework?  - Ah, non.
好吧 感謝你的誠實
Well, appreciate the honesty.
沒錯 我以前也討厭上學
Yeah, I used to hate school, too.
討厭學校的一切
Hated everything about it.
我高中輟學後 像我爸爸一樣在鑽井平台工作
Dropped out of high school, worked a rig like my daddy,
開始鑽井
started making hole.
你打算以後做什麼? 你也要鑽井嗎?
That what you gonna do? You gonna make hole?
- 是的 我想鑽井  - 不會吧
- Oui, I make hole.  - No shit.
知道嗎 你必須先做個學徒
You got to start out a worm, you know.
學徒是最低的等級
That's the lowest of the low. A worm.
不 不做學徒
Non, pas unworm.
我想和你一樣 在鑽井平台上工作
Je veux travailler sur le derrick, like you.
你要直接去井架嗎?
You going right to the derrick?
你必須要非常有動力
You got to have the want-to.
你有動力嗎?
You got the want-to?
嗯 有
Ben, oui.
嘿
Hey.
感謝您 主 為這和其他的祝福
Thank you, Lord, for this and other blessings.
請看護艾莉 繼續照看她
Please look after Ally. Keep a close eye on her.
我們奉耶穌之名祈禱 阿門
We ask this in Jesus' name. Amen.
- 開吃  - 開吃
- Dig in.  - Dig in.
- 晚上好  - 晚上好 媽媽
- Bonsoir.  - Bonsoir, maman.
- 嘿  - 嘿
- Hey.  - Hey.
- 如果你想要的話 上面有個漢堡  - 謝謝 啊
- There's a burger up there if you want it.  - Thanks. Ah.
給我的?
For me?
是的 女士 那是租金
Yes, ma'am. That's rent.
謝謝
Thank you.
請給我點番茄醬好嗎?
Would you please get me the ketchup?
你做家庭作業了嗎?
還沒有
Non.
晚飯後去做完
- 知道了  - 謝謝
- Mais oui.  - Thank you.
比爾 她必須做家庭作業
Bill, she has to do her homework.
我知道 這絕對應該
I know. Hundred percent.
做你的家庭作業
Do your homework.
- 是嗎?  - 嗯
- Yeah?  - Mm.
謝謝
Merci.
當我看到你吃飯時 我明白了你祈禱的原因
When I see what you guys eat, I understand why you pray before.
- 戲劇排練怎麼樣了?  - 還在排練
- How was play practice?  - Rehearsal.
呃 那很差勁
Uh, it was shit.
我們經常搞些即興舞台創作 所以很亂
We do a lot of stage writing, so it's messy,
還有 呃 導演... 他年輕而且保守
and, uh, the-the director... he's young and provincial.
什麼是即興舞台創作?
What's stage writing?
我們不知道該怎麼做 所以我們自己編劇
We don't know what we're doing, so we make it up instead.
很酷
Cool.
酷 拉烏爾
Cool Raoul.
}...第二局
凱利出現在展示他的技能
他後退一步 慢慢走到中間
Drops back, scrambles to the middle.
正在接近十碼線 但時間不多了
Down inside the ten, so the clock is running,
時間在飛逝
clock is running.
回去睡覺
Back to bed.
我能和你一起看嗎?
I look with you?
不行
No way.
去睡覺
Bed.
你會給我惹麻煩的
You're gonna get me in trouble.
我的平板電腦
My tablet.
對 我在用
Yeah, I'm using it.
現在睡覺
Bed, now.
...第四局 為什麼不呢?
...fourth quarter. Well, why not?
喂?
Hello?
對 就是他
Yeah, this is him.
這是一天的假期
It's a one-day leave.
她早上出去
She goes out in the morning,
晚上回到監獄
comes back to the prison at night.
如果進展順利
Then if it goes well,
她下個月還有一天
she'll get another day the following month.
這個想法是讓囚犯與外界接觸
The idea is for inmates to acclimate
以適應外面的世界
to the outside world again.
明白嗎?
Understand?
是的 女士 我明白
Yes, ma'am, I do.
法官需要一名監護人
The judge requires a chaperone,
一個為她擔保的人
someone who is going to vouch for her.
她要求是我嗎?
Did she ask for me?
不
No.
但你是唯一的選擇
But you are the only option.
好吧 艾莉森四個多月沒和我說過話了
Okay. A-Allison hasn't talked to me for more than four months.
我知道
I am aware.
貝克先生
Mr. Baker,
這次你什麼都不要做
do not take any initiative this time.
明白嗎?
Understand?
是 女士 我明白
Yes, ma'am, I do.
嗯?
Huh?
她喜歡的顏色
Color she love.
噢 她最喜歡的顏色?
Oh, her favorite color?
啊 是的 「最喜歡的」
Ah, oui,"favorite."
我不確定
Yeah, not sure.
嘿 瑪雅?
Hey, Maya?
不
No.
我覺得這很漂亮
I thought it was pretty.
比爾 比爾
Bill! Bill!
來看看! 看!
他住在馬賽! 他熱愛足球!
啊 足球 不 艾莉森喜歡俄克拉荷馬州大學球隊
Ah, soccer, no. Allison likes Oklahoma State.
她喜歡真正的足球
She likes real football.
這就是足球 我最喜歡的球隊
This is football, favorite foot.
不 這些傢伙就是群嬰兒
No, these guys are a bunch of babies.
一群愛哭鬼
Bunch of crybabies.
奧馬：奧利匹克馬賽足球俱樂部 (Olympique de Marseille)
不是嬰兒! 奧馬是世界上最好的球隊! 他們有很多偉大的球員!
帕耶特! 多萬! 酒井!
好吧 好吧 別生氣了 多少錢?
All right, all right, don't get all wound up. How much?
然後我們在街中間和音樂家一直表演
他們演奏打擊樂 每個人都和觀眾一起歌唱
媽媽
Maman.
- 媽媽 看! 比爾給我買了一件球衣!  - 哇 謝謝他了嗎?
嗯 還沒有
Euh, non.
謝謝 比爾
Merci, Bill.
- 好的  - 謝謝 比爾
- All right.  - Merci, Bill.
瑪雅 你還記得雷諾嗎?
- 記得  - 你好 瑪雅
- Oui.  - Bonjour, Maya.
你好
Bonjour.
嗨 你一定是比爾
Hi. You must be Bill.
是的 先生 你好
Yes, sir. Hi.
很高興見到你
Good to meet you.
維吉妮告訴我 你來自俄克拉荷馬
Uh, Virginie told me you-you are from Oklahoma.
那太棒了
That's so cool.
好吧
Okay.
雷諾是一位新星導演
Renaud is a rising star director.
就是我
That's me.
噢 你就是那個做舞台劇本寫作的人?
Oh, you're the one who does the stage writing?
是啊 你知道舞台劇本寫作嗎?
Yeah. You know about stage writing?
太好了
Great.
你知道 夥計 我真的很喜歡這個工作
Y-You know, man, I really love working like this.
很真實 知道嗎?
It's real, you know?
舞台劇本寫作? 是真實的
Stage writing? It's truth.
它來自生活
It's from life.
維吉妮已經告訴我了 對吧?
Virginie been telling me about it, right?
對 謝謝 比爾
Yeah. Merci, Bill.
呃 能幫我搬桌子嗎?
Um, would you help me move the table?
- 因為晚餐是...  - 行 我來搬
- 'Cause dinner is...  - Yeah, I got it.
謝謝 比爾
Merci, Bill.
說真的 對我來說 這很有意義
Seriously, for me, it makes total sense.
人們應該可以攜帶武器
People should be able to carry guns.
你說些什麼
知道嗎 但他們有這個自由
You know, but they got freedom.
這是基本自由
It's basic freedom.
我想要一把槍
I would love to have a gun.
我肯定你有把槍
I'm sure you have a gun.
- 是嗎 比爾?  - 是的 我有
- Don't you, Bill?  - Yes, sir, I do.
- 棒  - 不 你沒有
- Yes!  - No, you do not.
為什麼我沒有? 我有兩把
Why wouldn't I? I got two of them.
我有支獵槍 一把格洛克
I got a shotgun and a Glock.
- 噢 不 媽的 這不是真的  - 兩把槍 太完美了
- Oh, non, putain. C'est pas vrai.- Two guns! It's perfect!
不 不 停下 停下 沒關係
Non, non. Arrete, arrte. It's okay. It's okay.
這是他的...
It's-it's his...
- 他的... 他的文化  - 文化
- His-his... his culture.  - Culture.
文化是一個廣義的概念 是嗎?
Culture is such a broad concept, huh?
我今晚就到此為止 各位
I'm gonna call it a night, y'all.
拜託 比爾 時間還早
Come on, Bill. It's early.
- 我要帶瑪雅去睡覺  - 噢 我來
- I'll put Maya to bed.  - Oh, I can do it.
- 我去  - 好吧
- I got it.  - Okay.
你是我最喜歡的人
You're my favorite.
最喜歡什麼?
Favorite what?
我最喜歡的美國人
Favorite American.
做個好夢 小姑娘
Sweet dreams, little girl.
你知道今天是星期天早上 對嗎?
You know it's Sunday morning, right?
你的朋友呢?
Where's your friend?
噢 他一早就走了
Oh, he left early this morning.
嗯
Mm.
我們昨晚喝多了
We had a bit too much to drink.
這不廢話
Ain't no shit.
我在想 我想把艾莉森帶回這裡
I was thinking, uh, I'd like to bring Allison by the house.
這對她來說會不會太過了?
Won't it be too much for her?
我想讓她看看我住在哪裡
I'd like her to see where I live.
如果你同意的話
If you're okay with it.
為什麼我不呢?
Why wouldn't I be?
不是每個人都願意
Not everybody is.
- 嘿  - 嘿
- Hey.  - Hey.
這是你的貨車嗎?
This your van?
工作用的
From work.
什麼工作?
What work?
建築
Construction.
我在信中告訴過你這事
I told you about it in my letters.
你沒收到信嗎?
You didn't get them?
收到了
I did.
但我沒看
I didn't read them.
- 準備好出發了嗎?  - 好了
- You want to get going?  - Yeah.
謝謝
Merci.
哈姆迪·莉娜
1995 - 2014
你的家人想念你
生活是殘酷的
Life is brutal.
我可以開車嗎?
Can I drive?
□ 我被同胞出賣 □
□ I've been sacrificed by brothers □
□ 被愛人殘害 □
□ Crucified by lovers □
□ 但經歷這一切後... □
□ But through it all... □
我好久沒聽到這首歌了
I haven't heard this song in a while.
今天的特別播放列表
Special playlist for today.
那手機多少年了?
How old is that thing?
它一直能用
It still works.
□ 當我感到霧濛濛時 當我... □
□ When I get that foggy feeling when I'm... □
那你從沒想過回家?
So you never went home?
不想
Nope.
怎麼會?
How come?
□ 但要篤信會贏得最終的勝利 □
□ But it's hard to keep believing □
□ 時刻堅守 真的太難 □
□ I'll even come out even □
□ 當傾盆大雨砸落你的希望 □
□ While the rain beats your hope in the ground □
□ 今夜 我要決一死戰 浴血殺敵 □
□ And tonight it's really coming down □
□ 我... □
□ I'm... □
確定我們可以停在這裡嗎?
Are you sure we can park here?
他們要怎麼做?
What are they gonna do?
逮捕我嗎?
Arrest me?
奧馬
O.M.
你現在真的是本地人了
You really are a local now.
瑪雅說服我買了它
Maya sold me on it.
那是她最喜歡的球隊
That's her favorite team.
這孩子有父親嗎?
Does this kid have a father?
他不在這裡
He's not around.
住在海灘上或者別的什麼地方
Lives on a beach or some shit.
很不錯
Groovy.
那這個女人是你女朋友嗎?
So is this woman your girlfriend?
不是這樣的
It's not like that.
我只是和她們住在一起
I just live with them.
像室友一樣
Like roommates.
她是做什麼的?
What does she do?
她算是個演員
She's sort of an actress.
算個演員?
Sort of an actress?
她是脫衣舞女嗎?
She a stripper?
不是
No.
她不是在電視上演什麼的
She just don't do TV acting or anything.
她演戲
She does theater.
戲劇
Theater.
你看過她的演出嗎?
Have you seen her act?
我去該死的劇院幹嘛?
What am I gonna do in a fucking theater?
是啊
Yeah.
你知道什麼是困擾嗎?
You know what's messed-up?
我從來沒有機會去悼念她
I never had a chance to mourn her.
莉娜
Lina.
我們第一次見面時 氣氛非常緊張
It was so intense when we first met.
她很有趣
She was so funny.
又酷又漂亮
And cool and beautiful.
當她搬進來後 一切都亂套了
Then she moved in, and everything got fucked-up.
她開始和其他人上床
She started sleeping with other people.
還覺得這很正常
Like it didn't matter.
好像她只是在利用我
Like she was just using me.
或別的什麼
Or something.
我感覺非常羞辱
And I felt so humiliated.
但是 你知道 最可悲的事情是...
But, you know, the really fucked-up thing is...
...我就是想見到她
...I just want to see her.
我只想和她在一起
I just want to be with her.
非常渴望
So much.
看
是的
Oui.
準備好了嗎? 一 二 三
是的
Ouais.
啊
Ah!
不 不 不
Non, non, non!
他們到了!
- 你好  - 這是艾莉森
- Bonjour.  - This is Allison.
謝謝 爸爸 我想她知道
Thanks, Dad. I think she knew that.
我是維吉妮
I'm Virginie.
我是艾莉森
I'm Allison.
- 很高興認識你  - 很高興見到你
- Enchantee.  - Enchantee.
- 來吧 請進  - 謝謝
- Come. Come in.  - Merci.
瑪雅 來打個招呼
瑪雅? 瑪雅?
Maya? Maya?
到外面去
Get out here.
等等 稍等下
Wait. Attends.
我聞到了什麼
有沒有小動物躲在某個地方?
小貓咪?
你能講法語嗎?
好的
Ouais.
當然 我會說法語
所以 你一定是那個著名的瑪雅
是的
Oui.
你最喜歡的顏色是什麼?
我最喜歡的顏色...
...淺藍色和白色
奧馬的顏色!
- 加油 奧馬  - 加油 奧馬
我給你看我的房間
好的
Ouais.
監獄是什麼樣的?
不好玩...而且太熱了
- 你給我涂完後 我來幫你塗  - 我?
是的
Oui.
這樣 你回去的時候指甲才會好看
嘿 各位
Hey, y'all.
晚餐準備好了
- 啊 小心 那很燙 很燙  - 噢 那是...
- Ah, watch out. It's hot. It's hot.  - Ow, that's...
- 嗯 好 拿著這個  - 我來拿
- Yeah. Well, then take this.  - I got it.
我來拿 我來拿 我來拿
I got it. I got it. I got it.
看起來很美味
我們祈禱吧
Let's pray.
感謝主 為這和許多其他的祝福
Thank you, Lord, for this and many other blessings.
感謝您與艾莉度過這特別的一天
Thank you for this special day with Ally.
我們奉耶穌之名祈禱 阿門
In Jesus' name we pray. Amen.
瑪雅?
Maya?
開吃
Dig in.
- 給你  - 謝謝
- There you go.  - Merci.
謝謝
Thank you.
所以你倆真的沒有做過愛嗎?
So you two really aren't having sex?
艾莉森·貝克
Allison Baker.
什麼? 什麼?
What? What?
你現在很法國 我 我以為
You're so French now, I-I thought it was okay
在餐桌上討論性沒關係
to talk about sex at the dinner table.
抱歉
Sorry.
好吃嗎?
Is it okay?
食物
The food.
老實說 這是我很久以來
It's honestly the best meal I've had
吃過的最好一餐
in a really long time.
好
Good.
而且 我們從沒有過性行為
And, no, we don't have sex.
天哪
Jesus.
能給我些番茄嗎?
是的
Oui.
- 你喜歡番茄嗎?  - 是的! 你也喜歡嗎?
太喜歡了
你今天在哪裡吃的午飯?
So where did you have lunch today?
- 吃的比薩  - 比薩?
- Pizza.  - Pizza?
- 切斯索維爾 是我最喜歡的餐廳  - 噢
- Chez Sauveur. It's my favorite place.  - Oh.
- 是嗎?  - 非常美味
- Yeah?  - It's so good.
我很好奇 你為什麼來馬賽上學?
And, uh, I'm curious, why did you come to Marseille to study?
因為這裡遠離家
It was far away.
而且完全不同
And completely different.
還有比薩
And the pizza.
我也喜歡比薩
I like it, too.
他看起來很開心
生活不總是那麼容易 但他們相處得很好
真的嗎?
是的 他每天在她放學後都去接她
你父親對她說英語 她假裝聽懂了 很有趣
知道嗎 我媽媽去世後
他把我媽媽所有東西都收了起來
後來 我長大了
我想要一些她的東西
但我去儲物櫃時... 那裡什麼都沒有了
他無力償還債務 所以...
他們扔掉了我媽媽所有的東西
什麼也沒有留下
但現在他來了
他留下來是為了親近你
不要對我父親期望太高
他是個混蛋
He's a fuckup.
一直都是
Always has been.
那已經在他心中根深蒂固了
我知道是因為...
它也在我心中根深蒂固
牆的外面更精彩
It's more beautiful on this side of the wall.
我喜歡她們
I like them.
維吉妮和瑪雅
Virginie and Maya.
你有的這些都很好
It's good what you have.
我只是努力做正確的事
I'm just trying to do it right.
我為你高興 爸爸
I'm happy for you, Dad.
- 晚上好  - 晚上好
- WOBonsoir.  - Bonsoir.
允許重新進入
嘿
Hey.
你好嗎?
How are you doing?
很好
Pretty good.
是嗎?
Yeah?
今天過得好嗎?
The day was nice?
過得太快了
Flew by.
謝謝
Merci.
為什麼謝?
Pourquoi?
為一切 我想
Everything, I guess.
噢 晚安
Oh. Bonne nuit.
晚安
Good night.
喂?
Hello?
打擾下
Excuse me.
萊斯鮑梅特：馬賽第九區下面的一個區 馬賽中央監獄就在該區
我叫比爾·貝克 是艾莉森的父親 從萊斯鮑梅特過來的
I'm Bill Baker, father of Allison Baker, from Baumettes.
她怎麼了?
What happened to her?
這是什麼意思?
What does that mean?
上吊 上吊
好吧 我們現在得走了
嘿 先生 走吧 走吧
放開我
Fuck off me.
- 你可以在這裡等  - 你沒事吧 先生?
我不會拋下你 你也別拋下我
I don't leave you, you don't leave me.
她還好嗎?
Is she okay?
她很穩定
She's stable.
嘿 比爾
Hey, Bill.
我又和莎倫談過了
I talked to Sharon again,
告訴她你回來了
told her you was back in here.
而且我的工作也很順利
And work's been going good.
呃... 同事們都是好人
Uh... good group of guys.
16 17
16, 17,
18 16...
18, 16...
啊 比爾
Ah, Bill.
什麼 我說錯了嗎?
What, did I mess it up?
是的 你說錯了
Oui, you messed it up.
「一見鍾情
"Love at first sight.
我被你的眼神俘虜了」
I was trapped by how you looked at me."
燈
Lumiere.
Light.
帽子
Casquette.
Cap.
眼鏡
Glasses.
Lunettes.
謝謝 夥伴
Merci, hand.
這不是真實的
只是有個故事要講
瑪蒂爾德...
Mathilde...
...獨自在那所房子裡
而你呢...
...事故發生後的第二天 坐在廚房裡...
- 你不敢... - 謝謝你 維吉妮
我們休息一下
維吉妮 很好 跟隨燈光的節奏
好的
雷諾 我不知道我用這個櫃子幹什麼
你在尋找 保羅 你寧願和別人坐在一起嗎?
不 我寧願有個事可做 但這個沒有任何意義
我甚至不知道我應該找什麼
保羅 你要找的東西沒有答案 也沒有真相
啊 謝謝
Ah. Merci.
那麼 你怎麼看?
So, what did you think?
我怎麼看?
What'd I think?
對 這個劇 你覺得怎麼樣?
Yeah. Of the play. What did you think?
噢 很好 是的
Oh, it was good, yeah.
是嗎? 好在哪裡?
Yeah? What was good?
好...
Well...
我他媽不知道 我對戲劇一竅不通
I don't fucking know. I don't know shit about plays.
- 另外 這全是法語  - 拜託 比爾 說一個都行
- Plus, it's all in French.  - Oh, come on, Bill. One thing.
呃...
Um...
沒有人能像現實中的人那樣站著
Uh, no one stands like real people.
- 什麼?  - 看起來很奇怪
- What?  - It just looks weird.
聽著 演得很好 我確定
Look, it's great, I'm sure.
我不... 不要問我
I don't... D-Don't-don't ask me.
- 我太笨了  - 不 你不笨
- I'm a dumbass.  - No, you're not.
而且 演得也不太好 不好
And, no, it's not great, no.
啊 謝謝
Ah, merci.
乾杯
Cheers.
我要說 你...
I will say, you were...
演得真的很好
really good.
是台上最棒的
Best thing up there.
那麼 我有個好消息
So, I got exciting news.
我得到了這個角色
I got the part.
- 在電視節目上?  - 嗯
- On the TV show?  - Mm-hmm.
- 是的 我說過我能做到  - 你當然能
- Yeah, and I said I'd do it.  - No shit.
- 太好了  - 是啊
- That's great.  - Yeah.
但...
But...
這能掙更多錢 但工作時間也更長
it's more money, but it's also more hours,
那就意味著我必須雇個保姆
so that means I'll have to pay for a babysitter
而且我會經常離開瑪雅
and I'll be away more from Maya.
我也可以幫著照顧瑪雅
Well, I could help with Maya, too.
不 你幫得夠多了 知道嗎?
No, you help enough, you know?
你有工作 你也很忙
You got a job. You're busy.
我不在乎 我願意
I don't care. I want to.
為什麼?
Why?
- 為什麼?  - 嗯
- Why?  - Mm.
我喜歡和她在一起
I like spending time with her.
也喜歡和我嗎?
And with me, too?
對
Yeah.
也喜歡你和你在一起
And you, too.
你有多喜歡?
How much do you enjoy it?
很喜歡
A lot.
我想說很喜歡
I would say a lot.
這對我們來說會有一個重大改變
This would be a serious change for us.
我想會的
Guess it would.
你猜的?
You guess?
我是說 我知道
Well, I mean, I know.
噢
Oh.
那你知道...
And you know...
什麼?
what?
啊 看在老天份上
Ah, for fuck's sake.
- 你好 一切都好嗎?  - 是啊
- 進展順利嗎?  - 順利
你有現金嗎?
Do you have cash?
有 有
Yeah. Yeah.
嗯 要多少?
Uh, how much is it?
六十
Sixty.
不是吧?
No shit?
- 嘿  - 嘿
- Hey.  - Hey.
這是你的音樂
This is your music.
- 是啊  - 是呀
- Yeah.  - Yeah.
曲風有點悲傷 不是嗎? 也許我...
I-It's a bit sad, no? Maybe I...
- 啊 一點都不  - 嗯?
- Ah, hell no.  - Huh?
- 不 很美妙  - 是嗎?
- No, it's beautiful.  - Yeah?
對 你可以跟著音樂跳舞
Yeah, you can dance to it.
真的嗎?
Really?
不 不 不 過來
No, no, no. Come here.
過來
Come here.
我給你示範
I'll show you.
- 你給我示範?  - 對 我給你示範
- You show me?  - Yeah, I'll show you.
□ 過來躺在我身邊 □
□ Come and lay down by my side □
是薩米·史密斯的歌
This is Sammi Smith.
□ 直到清晨出現曙光 □
□ Till the early morning light □
□ 我想要的就是你的時間 □
□ All I'm taking is your time □
□ 幫我度過整個晚上... □
□ Help me make it through the night... □
噢 有雙眼睛在看著我們
Oh, we got eyes on us.
嗯...
Ben...
你不睡覺嗎?
不想
Non.
你想跳舞嗎?
想
Oui.
來吧
Viens.
□ 讓魔鬼帶走明天 □
□ Let the devil take tomorrow □
□ 但今夜我需要一個朋友 □
□ But tonight I need a friend □
嘿
Hey.
- 準備好了嗎?  - 嗯
- Ready for it?  - Mm-hmm.
□ 昨日已逝去 □
□ Yesterday is dead and gone □
□ 而明天已看不見... □
□ And tomorrow's out of sight... □
- 嘿  - 嗯?
- Hey.  - Huh?
- 我要問你一個事  - 什麼?
- I need to ask you something.  - What?
你真的有槍嗎?
Do you really own a gun?
噢
Oh.
兩把槍
Two guns.
- 嘿 瑪雅  - 嗯?
- Hey, Maya.  - Hmm?
能把頭盔遞給我嗎?
Want to hand me my casque?
什麼?
我的頭盔 我的頭盔 安全帽
My casque. My helmet. My hard hat.
- 噢  - 你能幫我拿嗎?
- Oh.  - Will you get it for me?
奧馬比賽的門票? 在室內球場嗎?
是的 女士
Yes, ma'am.
好
Ouais!
我要和比爾一起看奧馬的比賽了!
開始了
Here we go.
哇
Whoa!
是他! 10號迪米特裡·帕耶特! 他太棒了!
他沒有參加世界盃 因為他受傷了
噢
Oh.
哇
Wow.
該死 這地方越來越狂熱了
Damn, the place is heating up.
- 什麼?  - 好多球迷
- Quoi?  - A lot of fans.
都快瘋了
Going nuts.
應該有人告訴他們 他們贏了
Someone should tell them they're winning.
好吧 我們走
All right, let's go.
抱歉 抱歉 抱歉
Pardon, pardon, pardon.
比爾
Bill.
我們去哪裡?
噢 我想我看到個工作中的朋友
Oh, I think I see a friend from work.
我想確認是不是他
Want to see if it's him.
- 朋友?  - 是的 朋友
好了 我們去貨車那裡
Okay, let's go get the van.
- 是你朋友嗎?  - 不 不是他
- Is it your friend?  - No, that wasn't him.
- 嘿  - 嘿
- Hey.  - Hey.
- 怎麼樣?  - 嗯 很好 比賽剛剛結束
- How's it going?  - Uh, good. Game just ended.
馬上就回家
Be home soon.
- 好的 不用太急  - 是媽媽嗎?
- Okay, take your time.  - CC'est maman?
- 這是你的夜晚  - 好的
- It's your night.  - Okay.
嗯 稍後見
Uh, see you in a bit.
喔
Wouah!
回去睡覺
Go back to sleep.
繼續睡
Go on.
我們回家
We're going home.
你好
CCa va.
貝克先生
Mr. Baker.
很高興再次見到你
Nice to see you again.
你遲到了
You're late.
噢
Oh.
請原諒
Excusez-moi.
貝克先生 有什麼事嗎?
What can I do for you, Mr. Baker?
我們討論過的DNA測試... 我想把它做完
That DNA test we talked about... I want to get it done.
首先 我需要DNA樣本
First I will need, uh, the DNA sample.
我能問一下你是怎麼拿到的嗎?
Can I ask you how you got this?
你到底能不能做?
Can you do it or not?
是的 我能
Yes, I can.
但我是前警察 所以我告訴你
But I am an ex-cop, so let me tell you,
為了證明你女兒的清白而犯罪
it will be a serious mistake to commit a crime
將是一個嚴重的錯誤
to prove your daughter innocent.
這不會讓她出獄
It will not get her out of jail.
而會把你送進去
And it will send you in.
- 你明白嗎?  - 你多快能做出來?
- Do you understand?  - How fast can you do it?
這很難說
It's hard to say.
至少一個星期 但費用很昂貴
A week at least, but it will cost you.
這是3000美元
Here's 3,000 now.
你做完後我再給你3000
I'll give you another 3,000 when you get it done,
但必須一周內完成
but it's got to be quicker than a week.
即使匹配 我還是要找到這傢伙才行
Even if it matches, I still have to find this guy.
不 你不用
No, you don't.
你知道他在哪裡嗎?
You know where he is?
在結果出來前 他仍然可能消失
He could still disappear before the results come back.
他不會 完成後給我打電話
He won't. Call me when you get it done.
- 我們不去地下室嗎?  - 不 今天不去
來吧
Come on.
瑪雅?
Maya?
嘿 瑪雅?
Hey, Maya?
嘿
Hey.
- 好特別的招呼  - 你見過瑪雅嗎?
- This is quite a greeting.  - You seen Maya?
- 我在洗澡  - 是啊
- I was in the shower.  - Yeah.
她正在院子裡踢足球
She's playing soccer in the courtyard.
抱歉 我回來晚了
I'm sorry I'm late.
- 噢 沒事  - 那...
- Oh, that's all right.  - It...
你不想問我第一天上班的情況嗎?
Don't you want to ask me about my first day at work?
嗯 是啊 對 做得怎樣?
Uh, yeah, yeah. How'd it go?
那麼 進展如何?
為什麼? 告訴我
- 比爾?  - 嗯?
- Bill?  - Hmm?
地窖裡那個人是誰?
Who is the man in the cave?
地窖裡?
In the cave?
放工具那裡
With the tools.
我看見他了
I saw him.
我需要你的幫助
Um, I'm gonna need your help.
好嗎?
Okay?
因為這是個秘密
'Cause it's a secret.
你不能告訴任何人
You can't tell anyone.
甚至你媽媽
Even your mom.
好嗎?
Okay?
他是個壞人
He's a bad man.
他很快就會離開
He'll be gone soon.
這是我們的秘密
It's gonna be our secret.
好嗎?
Okay?
好姑娘
That's my girl.
我們不會從那個開始
媒體對她很不友好 可憐的孩子 他們把她描述成一個怪物
邪惡殘忍的美國女同性戀
巴托利在犯罪現場
那是場大屠殺 這是他說的 不是記者說的
拜託 她瘋了 她們在吵架
阿拉伯女孩欺騙了他 當情況和氣氛都很糟 就意味著...
糟透了!
但她的凶器一直沒找到 那把刀
你拿到了她的手機 你還想要什麼?
還有不明DNA? 她說是一個阿拉伯男孩的
那兒總是有不明DNA 送比薩的給你送貨來 然後出現了一個不明DNA
我不知道你對披薩送貨員做了什麼 但是...
送貨的是個女人
我不反對把阿拉伯人關起來 那個男孩拿走了她的鑰匙
並找到她的公寓 怎樣? 然後他沒有偷任何東西就刺傷了女朋友?
她可以責怪阿拉伯男孩 她可以責怪法國人
但確實是她殺了她的愛人 沒辦法 就是這樣 這就是愛
該死
Shit.
事實上 我學到了些新東西
I learned something new actually.
對我幫助很大
It's helped me a lot.
它被稱為「梅克圖布」
It's something called the "Mektub."
一位護士告訴我這個的
A nurse told me about it.
是關於接受
It's about acceptance.
接受什麼?
Acceptance of what?
命運
Your fate.
它讓我不再執著於掙扎
It's helping me to stop struggling so much.
不再質疑一切
Stop questioning everything.
你只是擁抱你的命運
You just embrace your fate
學會與命運和諧相處
and learn to live in peace with it.
這是一個穆斯林的理念
It's a Muslim idea.
是關於...
It's about...
放下所有的...
letting go of all of that...
...羞恥感...
...shame...
...和內疚感 這些都會
...and guilt that pushes you down
讓你悲觀
and keeps you down
讓你感到無力無助
and makes you feel so powerless.
這就是我長期以來的感受
And that's how I felt for a really long time.
無力和遺忘
Powerless and forgotten.
而且...
And...
這會讓生活變得很艱難
that makes living really hard.
明白我的意思嗎?
You know what I mean?
但你是無辜的
But you're innocent.
所以我們必須繼續抗爭
So we got to keep fighting.
我是無辜的並不重要 爸爸
It doesn't matter that I'm innocent, Dad.
這與正義無關
It's not about justice.
這是關於追尋寧靜
It's about finding peace.
請聽我說 就聽聽
我不是壞人 請讓我走
那不是我的錯
我不懂你在說什麼
I don't know what you're saying,
但你在白費口舌
but you're wasting your breath.
我們會等DNA結果 然後我們就會知道
We're gonna wait for that DNA, and then we'll know.
她讓我做的 她付錢給我
She ask me. She pay me.
你想要更多水嗎?
You want more water?
艾莉森 她說 「你去 趕走莉娜」
Allison, she say, "Go. You put Lina out."
- 夠了  - 「給你錢」
- That's enough, now.  - "Money for you."
夠了 現在
That's enough, now.
她讓我拿著它
She tell me take it.
她給了我一條項鏈
She gave me collier.
「你拿著它
"You take it.
- 過後付你錢」  - 給
- Money after."  - Here.
喝吧
Drink that.
繼續
Go on.
一條項鏈 「給你 你拿著它」
Un collier. "You take it for you."
項鏈 金的
Collier. Gold.
像這個 像這個
Like this. Like this.
項鏈? 我不想要那個
The necklace? I-I don't want that.
不
No!
她給了我
She gave me.
她說 「去 你把莉娜趕走
She say, "Go. You put Lina out.
先拿項鏈 事後付錢」
Necklace now. Money after."
你話都說不清楚
You're not even making sense.
是時候閉嘴了
Time to shut the fuck up.
靜水
S-Stillwater!
你說什麼?
What'd you say?
項鏈
The collier.
上面刻著「靜水」
He say "Stillwater."
金的
Gold.
她說...
She say...
「去做 讓她離開
"Do it. Make her go.
讓她出去」
Make her go out."
嘿
Hey.
- 嘿  - 你去哪兒了?
- Hey.  - Where were you?
我從萊斯鮑梅特走回來的
I walked back from the, uh, Baumettes.
我們得去看伊莎貝爾
We have to go and see Isabelle.
如果我們現在不去 就要遲到了
We'll be late if we don't leave now.
你 呃...
Do, uh...
我必須去嗎?
do I have to go?
是的 當然
Yes, of course.
我告訴過她你要去
I told her you were coming.
請快點 瑪雅...
Hurry up, please. Maya...
親愛的 穿上你的鞋 我們走!
好的 媽媽
Oui, maman.
伊莎貝爾
So, Isabelle is
對我們來說有點像教母
a sort of like godmother for us.
瑪雅真的很愛她
Maya really loves her.
哦 你會看到
Well, you'll see.
這是馬賽真正的的另一面
This is really the other side of Marseille.
教母
Marraine!
啊
Ah.
我不知道你在說什麼
I don't know what you're talking about.
她離開那天我給她的金項鏈
The gold necklace I gave her the day she left.
上面刻著「靜水」
Said "Stillwater" on it.
是的 我記得 它怎麼了?
Yeah, I remember it. What about it?
你還記得 她在審判時戴著它嗎?
D-Do you remember, was she wearing it at the trial?
她一直都戴著嗎?
Did she still have it on?
比爾 你發現了什麼?
What are you getting into, Bill?
我們去取她的東西時 你看到了嗎?
Wh-When we went to get her stuff, did you see it?
噢 我不知道
Oh, I don't know.
我不記得了 怎麼了?
I don't remember. Why?
我待會兒再跟你談 莎倫 再見
I'll talk to you later, Sharon. Bye.
沒事吧?
CCa va?
是啊 是 沒事
Yeah. Yeah, ca va.
呃 我在和莎倫通話
Uh, talking to Sharon.
- 她還好嗎?  - 好 她很好
- Is she okay?  - Yeah, yeah, she's fine.
那你呢?
Are you?
什麼意思?
What do you mean?
你看起來心不在焉
You just seem distrait.
是有點 抱歉
I am. Sorry.
我很高興你來這裡
I'm happy you're here.
我也是
Me, too.
你也是嗎?
You, too?
你很高興來這裡?
Y-You're-you're happy you're here?
- 是嗎?  - 我是
- Yeah?  - I am.
真的
Really.
我也是
Me, too.
我喜歡你 比爾·貝克
I like you, Bill Baker.
好了 來吧
Okay, come.
迪洛薩先生
Mr. Dirosa,
我是比爾·貝克
it's Bill Baker.
呃 我真的需要那個結果
Uh, really need that result.
嗯 有點緊迫
Uh, it's kind of urgent.
你好 女士
Bonjour, madame.
你好
Bonjour.
早上好 我是建設部門的 我被叫來是因為樓外牆出現一道裂縫
我想知道它是不是來自地下
你最近在這裡看到過什麼奇怪的東西嗎?
- 奇怪的? 在地下室?  - 任何情況 噪聲? 氣味?
- 我應該擔心嗎?  - 不 這只是例行檢查
- 你用地下室嗎?  - 我? 不用
樓裡還有其他人可能會使用地下室嗎?
如果你給我你的名片 我會調查並打電話給你
不用麻煩了 你已經幫了很多 女士
祝你今天愉快
Bonne journee.
再見
Au revoir.
知道嗎 在我小時候
You know, I used to fight a lot at school
經常在學校打架
when I was a kid, too.
但那不好 打架? 不好
But that's not good. Fight? No.
那不好
你確定你不要這個?
You sure you don't want this?
地下室裡的人
The man in the cave,
你會殺了他嗎?
you will kill?
什麼? 不
What? No.
當然不會
Of course not.
聽我說
我永遠不會做任何傷害你或你媽媽的事
I would never, ever do anything to hurt you or your mother.
永不
Never.
因為我愛你們兩個
Because I love both of you.
非常愛
So much.
我知道
I do.
你必須相信我
You just have to trust me.
好嗎?
Okay?
好的
Okay.
貝克先生 請談幾句
Mr. Baker, a word please.
警察
Police.
能看看你的身份證嗎?
Can I see your I.D. please?
你的身份證 貝克先生
Your I.D., Mr. Baker.
謝謝
Thank you.
把帽子摘下來
Take off your cap.
好的 謝謝
Okay. Thank you.
貝克先生 我的同事們
So, Mr. Baker, my colleagues
要把小女孩帶進去
are gonna take the little girl inside.
好嗎?
Okay?
- 不 比爾  - 好吧 好吧 好吧
- No, Bill.  - Okay, all right, all right, all right.
沒事 沒事的
It's okay. It's all right.
- 你和她一起去  - 不
- You go with her.  - No.
會好的 會好的
Tout va bien. Tout va bien.
沒事的
It's all right.
你沒事的
You're all right.
貝克先生 看著我
So, Mr. Baker, look at me.
這裡有地下室嗎?
Do you have a basement here?
有還是沒有?
Yes or no?
- 有 警官  - 好的
- Yes, sir.  - Okay.
請把鑰匙給我
Give me the keys please.
我去檢查
請吧
Please.
停
Stop.
我會檢查
沒有
停
Stop.
最後一扇門有鎖
你有鑰匙嗎?
Do you have the key?
貝克先生
Mr. Baker.
他拿到了
He's got it.
在鑰匙鏈上
沒有
我們上樓
Let's go upstairs.
坐下
Sit.
- 我們已經搜過了 沒有  - 她說她什麼都不知道
介意我問你女兒一些問題嗎?
是的 我介意 她才9歲
你寧願去警察局嗎?
你叫瑪雅 對吧?
來吧
Viens.
去吧 親愛的
Vas-y, cherie.
比爾和你還有你媽媽住在這裡? 是這樣嗎?
看著我
是的
Oui.
他對你好嗎?
- 是的  - 嗯
- Oui.  - Ah.
你去過地下室嗎?
是的
Oui.
你在那裡做什麼?
我們一起整理工具 我教比爾法語單詞
啊
Ah.
你最後一次去地下室是什麼時候?
昨天
昨天?
而且一切正常?
你認識比爾的女兒艾莉森嗎?
認識 她在監獄裡
你不希望比爾進監獄 是嗎?
- 不想?  - 不想
- Non?  - Non.
因為你喜歡他嗎?
- 是的  - 嗯
- Oui.  - Mm.
現在聽好 如果你騙我 我會知道的
那我將不得不把比爾送進監獄
你明白嗎?
讓我重複這個問題
你上次去地下室是什麼時候?
昨天
好吧
Okay.
我們走
你放了他嗎? 那個人?
去你的房間
快去!
維吉妮 我不是有意...
Virginie, I didn't mean to...
你怎麼找到他的?
How did you find him?
純屬偶然
Pure chance.
在一場足球比賽中
The soccer game.
和瑪雅看的那場?
With Maya?
你叫她撒謊了?
Did you ask her to lie?
你有嗎?
Did you?
我從來沒想過要把你和瑪雅牽扯進來
I never meant to involve you or Maya.
- 我知道...  - 你...
- I know...  - You...
你現在必須離開
You have to leave now.
好吧 你收拾好東西就走
Okay. You pack your things, you leave.
我可以進來嗎?
May I come in?
瑪雅?
Maya?
你不想和我說話?
You don't want to talk to me?
好吧
All right.
很抱歉
I'm sorry.
非常抱歉
I'm so sorry.
我愛你
I love you.
比爾
Bill.
不
Non.
去跟比爾道別 快去! 去吧!
貝克先生
Mr. Baker,
我帶來了些非同尋常的消息
I've come with some extraordinary news.
你女兒案件的法官今天早上打電話給我
The judge in your daughter's case called me this morning.
新的證據已經浮出水面
New evidence has surfaced.
看起來 是一名退休警察
Apparently, a retired cop
在不明來源DNA樣本上找到一個匹配
came up with a DNA match on the unknown sample.
它也與警方四年前在一起
It also matched a sample the police collected
已審判的盜竊案中
on a burglary case four years ago,
採集的樣本相符
after the trial.
抓到他了嗎?
Did they catch him?
不 還沒有
No, not yet.
但我們只需要證明案子有足夠的疑點
But all we need to prove is sufficient doubt.
所以即使他們找不到嫌疑犯
So even if they can't find the suspect,
他們也很可能會釋放艾莉森
there's a real chance they will release Allison.
事實上 法官已經同意
In fact, the judge has already agreed
重新開始調查 這是以前從未有過的
to reopen the investigation, which is almost unheard of.
我想這種事只能發生在馬賽
I think this could only happen in Marseille.
謝謝你來告訴我 女士
Thank you for coming to tell me, ma'am.
貝克先生 這對你的家人來說是最好的結果
Mr. Baker, this is the best possible outcome for your family.
你明白嗎?
Do you understand?
我明白
I do.
謝謝你 女士
Thank you, ma'am.
加油 波克斯
Go, Pokes!
我說過我們要帶我們的姑娘回家
I told you we were gonna bring our girl home,
並且我們確實做到了
and that's exactly what we did.
歡迎回家 艾莉森
Welcome home, Allison.
歡迎回到俄克拉荷馬
Welcome back to Oklahoma.
歡迎回到美國
Welcome back to America!
你不合群嗎?
You're being antisocial?
你沒事吧?
You all right?
你去馬賽的那天
The day you left for Marseille,
莎倫和我開車送你去機場 然後...
Sharon and I drove you to the airport, and...
我們到那裡時
when we got there,
我很尷尬我沒有禮物或者別的什麼給你
I was embarrassed I didn't have a present or nothing,
所以我去了禮品店
so I went to the gift shop.
我想給你買本書或者鑰匙扣什麼的
I thought I'd get you a book or a key chain or something.
然後我看到了這條項鏈
Then I saw this necklace.
我想它對你來說就像帶著家的一角
I thought it'd be like a little piece of home to take with you.
它是金的
It was gold.
上面刻著「靜水」
Said "Stillwater" on it.
我不想發生這種事
I didn't want it to happen.
他告訴我他會幫我
He told me that he would just help me
把她趕出公寓 就是這樣
get her out of the apartment, that's all.
我不想讓她死
I didn't want her to die.
我愛她
I loved her.
我知道你愛她
I know you did.
你覺得我是個怪物嗎?
You think I'm a monster?
你是我女兒
You're my daughter.
我... 我永遠不會這麼想
I... I could never think that.
爸爸 我們錯了嗎?
Dad, what is wrong with us?
我不知道 小寶貝
I don't know, baby girl.
我不知道
I don't know.
很抱歉
I'm sorry.
非常抱歉
I'm so sorry.
很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我也很抱歉
Me, too.
□ 取下我頭髮上的絲帶 □
□ Take the ribbon from my hair □
□ 抖松讓它落下 □
□ Shake it loose and let it fall □
□ 輕輕地貼在你的皮膚上 □
□ Lay it soft against your skin □
□ 就像牆上的影子... □
□ Like the shadows on the wall... □
早上好
Morning.
嘿
Hey.
我睡不著
Couldn't sleep.
就去散步 然後...
Went for a walk, and...
最後又回到這裡了
ended up here.
我很高興你回這裡
I'm glad you did.
你想她們嗎?
You miss them?
當然想
I do.
你會回去嗎?
Can you go back?
不 我不會
No, I can't.
但那段經歷很好
But it was good.
這永遠不會改變
That don't change.
很抱歉
I'm sorry.
生活很殘酷
Life is brutal.
這裡一切看起來都還一樣
Everything looks the same here.
什麼都沒變
Nothing's changed.
你不覺得嗎?
Don't you think?
不 艾莉 我不覺得
No, Ally, I don't.
對我來說這裡一切都變了
It all looks different to me.
我幾乎都認不出來了
I don't hardly recognize it anymore.
導 演
湯 姆·麥 卡 錫
編 劇
湯 姆·麥 卡 錫  馬 庫 斯·辛 奇
托 馬 斯·彼 得 葛 恩  諾 亞·德 勃 雷
主 演
馬 特·達 蒙
靜 水 城
卡 米 爾·科 坦
阿比蓋爾·佈雷斯林
利 魯·肖 沃